You showed us the path to glory...
with your holy words, 0 Prophet.
Allow me to acknowledge
my fellow brothers.
Essalam u aleyku m
- Es-selamu aleykilm.
- Aleykume selam.
What did our Prophet say, Eyyub?
Our Prophet said:
"Konstantiniyyah will
definitely be conquered one day."
The commander who conquers
it is a blessed commander.
"His soldiers are blessed soldiers."
In the year when Mehmet...
who would have the honor of becoming
that blessed commander when he was 12...
was born, many
miracles were witnessed.
Horses gave birth to
a lot of twin babies.
The land gave crops
four times in a year...
The branches of the trees bent down to
the ground because of the heavy fruits.
The comet observed over
Constantinople in the same year...
was considered as a sign that...
the unbreakable walls
of the city would fall.
EDIRNE
MARCH 29, 1432
SURA Of CONQUEST
Huma Hatun gave a
healthy boy, my Sultan.
Let him name Mehmet to show
our respects to our Prophet.
I gave him his name, may
Allah give him his fate.
SARUHAN POST
I told you...
I was going to defeat
you one day, Hasan.
And I told you that would be the
happiest day for me, my Sultan.
We have a letter from Halil
Pasha in Edirne, my Sultan.
Sultan Mehmet was only twelve
when he first took the throne.
Sultan Murat ll, who
had been tired of...
the inner conﬂicts between
his viziers and his warlords...
had decided to leave the
throne to his son, Mehmet...
after the unexpected death
of his favorite son, Aladdin.
But, Grand Vizier Halil Pasha made
Sultan Murat come back to his throne...
because of a possible
threat of another Crusader Army
And Mehmet was sent to Saruhan Post.
You had strong arms...
to conquer the cities
and bring the armies to heel.
They did not hold me not even for once.
You had sharp eyes seeing
the future of our governance.
They never...
looked at me tenderly.
They never saw how much I love you.
My heart was dying to kiss
the land you stepped on.
And now it is dying
to conquer the lands...
you will never be
able to step on, father.
To build a world-wide empire.
Why do my father's viziers stand aside?
Stand next to me
appropriate to your offices.
I returned to my birth-right
throne five years later.
What do you think about it, Halil Pasha?
You were...
too young at the time, my Sultan.
The Crusaders had passed the
Danube to expel us from Rumelia.
We asked...
your father to take back the throne.
It was all for the
sake of our government.
If you think...
this was a mischief...
then our lives are in your will.
I don't doubt that.
Therefore, for the sake
of our government...
I assign you the grand vizier.
Sahabettin, Zaganos and
Saruca will also be my viziers.
Murat Bey is dead, your majesty.
Sultan Mehmet took the
throne for the second time.
I see that you are as happy as I am...
for hearing the news.
Not me, your majesty.
It seems that...
Grand Duke Notaras fears that he will
besiege the city like his father did.
Just remember why Sultan Murat...
was forced to retreat from the siege.
It was enough for us to declare
Prince Mustafa as the sultan.
Even though...
the poor prince died
before he fulfilled his dreams.
Now we have even a
stronger sultan candidate.
Prince Orhan.
With all my respect...
this is delusional.
Sultan Mehmet's only desire
is to destroy our empire.
He studied sciences of
engineering to break our defences.
He studied our language to
understand our weaknesses.
And he studied our religion
to strangle our faith.
He might be too young right now.
But he is...
the anti-Christ.
Grand Duke Notaras, cease worrying.
Mehmet is an already overthrown Sultan.
He has no dignity in his own people.
We will show him our power...
before he will know it.
Send an envoy to Edirne.
Let Mehmet see our peaceful policies.
You are getting younger, old man.
And teaching the sultan to hold
a sword with his gentle hands...
did not lessen you, Hasan. Come here.
He learnt to use the sword from
you. But what about the reign?
Who will he learn to rule from?
You either have it or not.
Murat Bey was not like him.
We fought together with
him in Varna and Kosovo
I'm ready to scarify not one but
all my eyes for a sultan like that.
But Mehmet...
Be fair, master.
Our sultan was 12 years old back then.
Nobody cares about his age.
Was he on the throne? He was.
Was he overthrown? He was.
That's what people need to
know. They don't care the rest.
How would you like it, if
the infidels' dummy Orhan...
had taken the throne?
You don't know his virtues.
You will regret your words
when the day comes, master.
VATICAN
Sultan Mehmet...
will be determined about
what his father started.
And don't doubt that...
his next destination will be Rome.
Emperor Constantine has to obey
the resolution taken in Florence...
about joining the churches.
We have to put pressure if necessary.
That's right. The biggest threat...
for that infidel Turk
is the Orthodox people...
praying for thr
Holy See and the Pope.
We should benefit from
his inexperience...
to get rid of the Ottomans for good.
Constantinople...
will either be a Moslem
capital or a Catholic capital.
I don't think Sultan Mehmet is
braver and smarter than his father.
But we have to consider
all the possibilities.
We can't leave Constantinople
to the infidels.
God is on our side.
KARAMANOGLU PRINCIPALITY KONYA
You are right, he assigned
Halil Pasha as his grand vizier.
He can't even get rid of someone
who took the throne away from him.
We should take advantage of this weakness.
Spread the word to other principalities.
It is the right time to
get rid of the Ottomans.
I am pleased...
with the beautiful words your
emperor had said about my late father.
And about Orhan...
Your emperor wants to
raise his subsidy...
to 300,000 coins.
It is important for our dynasty
that he lives a comfortable life
I will give my orders.
Tell your emperor that he will receive
the friendship he desires to build.
Do you believe Constantine's
sincerity, Mentor?
Neither his courage nor his strength
is enough for him to cross the line.
Contact...
with the Latin, Hungarian, Polish and
the Serbian king, and also with the Pope.
Tell them that we want to
live in peace with them.
Yes, my Sultan.
You can leave now.
Zaganos and Sabahttin Pashas, you stay.
I see that you are not
happy with my decisions.
It is not our place
to question the Sultan.
However, we might have
something to say...
if you discuss with us
before you give an order.
We don't have a more important duty...
other than conquering Konstantiniyyah
for the sake of our government.
We have to be patient until we
eliminate all the obstacles...
one by one and take over the city.
Mother. I really missed my father.
Not "father", but "my sultan."
So what will you call him?
My Sultan.
My Sultan...
I know there is a reason
for everything you do...
but...
giving Halil Pasha back his office...
and compromising with
Constantine caused disappointment
within your subjects.
It is considered as weakness.
I fear that if we cant win the trust...
of both our people and the army...
then we can have some
very serious problems.
Government...
is not a place of
displaying power, Zaganos.
It is a tool...
to protect their interest...
provide them wealth and
build a future for them.
Thats what makes a sultan powerful.
Dont worry.
When the time comes, my
army and my subjects...
will understand why
I made these decisions.
Check.
Welcome, Gulbahar Hatun.
It was a very long way, my Sultan.
But it is worth seeing you.
Yes, father!
My sultan.
Your son, Prince
Bayezid missed you a lot.
He called your name even
while he was sleeping.
Come on.
Go and have a rest.
Have you taken your luggage?
- Have a nice voyage.
- Era.
I caught you in the last minute.
I talked to the Duke one more last time.
But I couldn't convince him.
He is not interested in
your new crane designs.
I thought so.
But he said you can...
immediately build a cannon
foundry if your father accepts.
You know my father. He wont accept.
I know. And I told the Duke, too
Thank you for everything. I
appreciate what you have done for me.
Goodbye.
Era.
Dont go.
Marry me.
We shall bring your father here, too.
And I can convince the Duke in time.
Actually, I can even convince the Duke
to build a dockyard for your father.
I told you.
You will always be a very
valuable friend for me.
He just cant sleep, my lady.
Why didn't you go to sleep, my son?
Dont sultans love
their children, mother?
What are you talking about, Bayezid?
You will understand how much our
Sultan loves you as you grow up.
My son.
Mehmet.
I am your grandfather, Osman
I founded our principality.
My successors, your
forefathers, your father...
turned this principality
into a strong state.
And you will turn it
into a mighty empire.
You deserve this ring the most.
You are that righteous commander
who was acknowledged by...
our Prophet.
May Allah bless your campaign.
Your highness!
Are you alright?
Either I will conquer Konstantiniyyah...
or Konstantiniyyah will conquer me.
Isa Pasha.
Give my orders to the
dockyard in Gallipoli.
They should be able to
make 100 ships in a year.
Yes, my Sultan.
Sahabettin Pasha, I need the
foundry to make 3 huge crucibles.
Yes, my sultan.
Zaganos. Hasan? - He is already
in Konstantiniyyah, my Sultan.
Halil Pasha, and I want a full report...
about the gears and the
munitions of the janissaries.
Yes, my Sultan.
My Sultan, may I ask...
what all these preparations are for?
They are for joining our
state which is divided...
in Rumelia and Anatolia
together and make it a big empire.
I know what you mean, my Sultan.
But I am afraid...
there is a risk of shrinking and even
getting destroyed while trying to expand.
Making no progress already
means to die. Pasha.
We need to make bold decisions
for the future of our people.
Here is something very important
my ancestors taught me, Mentor:
Making history...
is no job for the cowards.
Leave it, you bastard.
Don't run. Come here. Catch him.
Come here.
- Stop.
-  I am very sorry.
What have you done? Damn you.
- Stop. Dont hit me.
- Just watch where you are going.
- I tripped. What can I do about it?
-  You made fall down.
Where is the kid?
Where is that bastard?
Where did he hide? Anybody seen him?
Come on. Run.
So, how was the voyage?
It was no fun without you.
But not bad anyway.
- We had a storm for a while, actually.
-  Really?
By the way...
I got the book you asked me.
So tell me. What did the Duke say?
He is not interested
in our designs, father.
The fake noble.
He doesn't see the value
of the cranes I designed.
He has other things in his mind.
He wants you to make
cannons for his army.
They can go to hell.
Doesnt he know that I wont
make cannons for anyone anymore?
And what about Guistiniani?
The same.
He proposed me as always.
And you said no, as always.
Constantine invited
Orhan to dinner tonight.
Lets meet after the dinner.
To our Turkish friend.
We are informed that
Karamanoglu Ibrahim...
is making preparations for
a campaign against Sultan Mehmet.
Who do you think will win...
if he can find a strong support?
Karamanoglu, naturally.
Its not only us. Halil of
Candar thinks like that, too
Theres only one thing you should
do to take your righteous throne.
Help Karamanoglu Ibrahim Bey.
I am ready to do whatever it takes.
You can write a letter saying
that we all support Karamanoglu..
Including Halil Pasha, the
Latins, the Pope, and Hungarians.
You can even offer him some land.
If you do that, I will send
two different messengers...
from different routes to make
sure that it reaches Ibrahim Bey.
And we will watch whats coming next.
This is the letter Constantine
told Orhan to write...
and addressed to Karamanoglu Ibrahim.
Good job, Hasan.
The second courier group
must be about to arrive...
at Karamaoglus with a copy
of this letter, my Sultan.
Our plan works.
Karamanoglu started the campaign.
He fell into our trap.
He will be swept away if he
is defeated by Karamanoglu.
It doesn't matter even if he defeats.
His army will have heavy losses.
So he wont be able to mess
with us for a very long time.
Besides, we should double the
subsidy for Orhan to 600,000 coins.
Youll see, he will have to accept it.
And while my treasure raises,
whatever dignity he has left...
in the eyes of his
own people will diminish.
KARAMANOGLU PRINCIPALITY AKSEHIR 1451
I thought Halil of Candar
Pasha would support us.
Without Halil Pashas support...
he can't possibly gather such
a big army in such a short time.
The letter was nothing but
a big lie. We are fooled.
There is no way we can
have a victory if we fight.
Karamanoglu Ibrahim asks for peace. Lie!
He wants to provide us soldiers
and serve for our cause.
If we leave this pander alone now,
he will uprise again in
the first opportunity.
This is not the way to govern.
Our army will have heavy
causalities if we fight.
I think it is better for us
to accept his offer, my Sultan.
This is crazy.
Your policies are nothing
but a bunch of coward actions.
I think my mentor is right.
He wont be able to dare
anything for a very long time.
He wont cause us any problems during
our campaign to Konstantiniyyah.
Go now.
Bring me that pander.
Bring him in.
Stand up.
Dont forget...
you can battle with anyone...
but you make peace
only with honorable men.
I swear on my honor. No
more blood will be spilled...
as long as I live.
You will carry that honor of
yours until your last breath.
Or, your death shall come by my hand.
Who knows...
maybe this is your destiny.
- My Sultan?
- Read it.
Constantine...
wants to double the subsidy
we pay for Orhan, my Sultan.
There is no obstacle for doing this.
Yet, this is neither the
right time nor the place.
He wants to take advantage
of us being in a campaign.
Out.
Mentor, you stay here.
I thought they didn't have any
other option but stay friendly?
I thought they didn't have neither
the courage nor the strength.
Is this your idea of friendship, mentor?
Is this your idea of friendship?
Come here.
I happened to capture...
this letter written
by Orhan to Ybrahim.
Read it.
Here is what surprised me the most:
That serpent Orhan, says to
other serpent named Ybrahim
The Grand Vizier Halil
Pasha supports me.
But this should be secret for now.
Mighty Allah is my witness.
I have nothing to do with this letter.
I never left your father's path...
or your path in my entire life.
We will talk about this
when we go back to Edirne.
Now you can go.
Sultan Mehmet wanted to break Halil
Pasha's influence on the soldiers...
who was now in a very bad
position because of the letter.
On the way back home, some
soldiers asked for guerdon...
even though they hadn't actually
fought. He used this opportunity.
With the pretext of deserted
soldiers he punished...
Janissary Master Kurtcu
Doban and his fellow janissaries.
Bu kendini bilmez Send these
blatant reptiles to exile.
Yes, my Sultan.
Each of the blows these guys have
is actually addressed to me, Isa.
Karamanoblu, eh?
Cowards.
They surrendered not
even drawing their swords.
Sultan Mehmet figured that our
friendship policy is a game.
He is not young and inept any more...
but a Sultan with his first victory.
You can be sure that
he wont send a dime...
of the 300,000 coin subsidy
he had agreed for Orhan.
Isnt it enough that you worried?
How come such a letter can be written?
How dare he use my name in this letter?
Our Sultan knows that this is a trick.
Even if he doesn't, he cant
dare to do anything to you.
He doesn't want to cause
internal conﬂicts.
You re wrong, Emine.
He is taking control of
the government step by step.
Our Sultan wants you in
his presence, my Pasha.
Oh my... This late.
This...
means only one thing.
Go and bring my shroud.
(I witness there is no God but Allah)
(And I witness Mohammed is
his servant and his Prophet.)
Approach.
Give my mentor some water.
L...
never doubted your loyalty.
Otherwise...
you would have been beheaded already.
Acknowledge Constantine that we
wont be paying the subsidy any more.
Yes, my Sultan.
Come here.
What do you see?
I see the fort built my your heavenly
grandfather Sultan Bayezid, my Sultan.
What do you see, now?
A new fort in Rumelia, my Sultan.
We will build...
a new fort right here
in Boéazkesen, mentor.
You will be in charge of
building these two bastions.
The moment we put the first stone...
Constantine, Pope and
the Latin governments...
will know what we are up to.
They will join forces and attack us.
Neither the Latins...
nor the Pope...
nor Constantine.
My only concern is my subjects...
who cant realize that its for their
interest to conquer Konstantiniyyah.
The blood will spill anyway.
The question is...
is it to become a
martyr or just to be wasted.
BODAZKESEN,
APRIL 1452
We will be able to control all
the ships coming from Black Sea.
Our Sultan.
Keep working.
He is building a fort
right in front of us.
He will intercept the cargo
ships coming from the Black Sea.
He will make us starve.
He is preparing for a siege.
We should immediately
get ready for a war.
Send a word to Mora, my brothers.
Tell them to come here with their army.
Remind Guistiniani my offers.
Tell him that I will give him Limnos
Island if he commands my armies.
And this cannon founder...
- whats his name, Notaras?
- Urban, your majesty.
Convince him to make stronger
cannons than we already have.
You were right.
Sultan Mehmet clearly revealed his
intention by starting to build that fort.
His holiness should take some action.
Mehmet will be discouraged if
we gather a strong Crusader army.
And Emperor Constantine...
will have no option
other than approving...
- ...the unification of churches.
- True. But...
Frenchmen and Englishmen are already
devastated because of their ongoing war.
And the German king is
struggling for his crown.
And Mehmet is aware of all. He
must have considered all these.
Yet, Pope may perhaps convince
Venetians and Genoeses.
We should send a messenger
to Constantine any way.
Youure right.
He should know about our efforts.
We expect to finish the
fort in 11 months, my Sultan.
We have 5 months at most.
We have to take control of the strait...
to intercept any aid
going to Konstantiniyyah...
before and during the siege.
We will all carry rocks if necessary.
My Sultan, Constantine asked help...
from Mora just like
you were expecting.
I am sorry to see...
your unacceptable
attempts to cut off...
the route from my city to Black Sea.
Your intention is obvious.
You think you can pass over my walls.
You will be disappointed...
just like your late father.
You stopped paying
the subsidy for Orhan...
because of a letter which
has nothing to do with us.
We didn't protest it for the
sake of peace between us.
But if...
you don't stop building
the fort immediately...
I will send Orhan to Edirne...
and do all I can for him
to take over your throne.
And...
you must be in delusion...
if you think that
Pope and the Latins...
will ignore your actions.
You will have to counter a Crusader
army of an unprecedented magnitude.
He says he will make Orhan the Sultan.
He should stop the plot he has
been keeping on for centuries.
He must know best who my
people and my army support.
And Pope gathering a Crusader army?
Be my guest.
We will defeat them
again just like we did...
in Varna and Kosovo.
I am...
not like my predecessors.
I am Sultan Mehmet Han.
If I want to make a fort in Rumelia
in my governance, then I do it
Everything in my land...
is under my command.
Mehmet wont stop building the fort.
And he has started to gather
a big army in Anatolia.
We started the production
as you ordered, your majesty.
We will burn him and his
army with our Greek fire.
And Pope says he is
determined to support us.
But as you know, with his condition
that our church abides him.
Why don't we send Orhan to Edirne and
let him provoke people against Mehmet?
Thats impossible. His people
and his army supports him.
Then why do we still feed him?
Mehmet will not be able to pass
the walls. And this will be his end.
What is more precious than having
someone on the throne loyal to us?
- Are the cannon foundries ready?
- Theyre renewed, your majesty.
I will talk to Urban, today.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- Father, we should also buy salt.
- Alright, my girl.
Engineer Urban. Grand
Duke Notaras wants you.
Father?
You go back home. Theres
nothing to worry about.
Lets go.
Welcome, Engineer Urban.
As you know, our city is
fighting against the infidels.
This is not my fight, sir.
All Christians should fulfill
their duties. Including you.
I have neither the desire nor the strength
to mold the cannons you want. Forgive me.
Think about your daughter, not yourself.
We don't want that beautiful
girl get hurt, do we?
You have time till morning
to change your mind.
You can go now.
Come on, hurry up.
We have to go before Notaras dogs come.
You are arrested by the
order of Grand Duke Notaras.
Seize them.
Leave my daughter alone.
Don't touch me, you jerk.
Sultan Mehmet wishes
to see you in his court.
We are informed that...
those were Turks who kidnapped Urban.
Rascal.
He will attack my walls
with the cannons Urban makes.
Find away to kill Urban.
We have news from Mora,
your brothers, your majesty.
Mehmets soldiers have burnt down Mora.
They killed all the troops...
of your brothers.
God damn Turk.
He is always one step ahead. Always.
We are sorry to take
you to Edirne by force.
Actually you made a big favor to us.
Helping your sultans cause...
may help me conclude
a personal matter.
What is it?
Years ago, the Crusader army
also supported by Constantine...
to wipe you out from the Balkans...
burnt down all the
Moslem villages on their way.
Including our village, too.
They slaughtered my family.
I found myself in the slave
market in Constantinople.
If it wasnt Urban who
pitied and bought me...
So, Urban is not your father.
He is like a father to me.
Engineer Urban has been
my father since then.
Come on, we should start
as soon as possible.
I am master at moulding
cannons as much as my father.
But we cant have a girl in the foundry.
Dont worry. They wont see a girl.
Let's go.
Come on, Father.
We don't have any other option.
Write a letter to Pope.
Tell him that I am ready to host...
a united ceremony with Catholic
and Orthodox people within my lands.
It is time to become united...
against the anti-Christ.
If we call the Latins, they
will never leave our city.
Did you forget what they had done to us?
They harmed our faith and our
city more than anybody else.
Mehmet will take action as soon as
he can. We don't have time to lose.
I implore you, your highness.
This decision will take our
religion under Pope's command.
This means the end of our faith.
I prefer seeing Turkish
turban in the city...
rather than the Latin cone.
We don't want the faithless
Catholics in Hagia Sophia.
We won't give away our religion to Pope.
We won't pray in the same
church with the Latins.
We don't want their prayers.
They're trying to take over our faith.
It is time to say no to
these lousy Catholics...
who feed on the blood of
real Christians like ourselves...
who follow jesus.
Engineer Urban...
I am pleased to see you
and your assistant with us.
Thank you, your highness.
I want you to make a cannon big enough
to break the walls of Konstantiniyyah.
Something never will be
seen in history again.
We can cast the cannon
as big as you want.
Hasan will be here all the time
to provide your safety and needs.
- May your job be easy.
- Thank you, your highness.
May Allah...
make our efforts free from troubles
Don't let us fail.
- Let our soldiers be victorious.
- Amen.
(Power and strength
only come from Allah)
- Allah is great.
-  Allah is great.
- Do you need help, engineer Elias?
- What?
We can't call you Era in public, can we?
Shut up. I look like a boy.
I think you are as beautiful
as you were in the market.
BOGAZKESEN SEPTEMBER 1452
Oh my. The rumors are true.
Turks have accomplished a miracle.
They signal us to stop.
We are not going to stop
just because they want so.
Sink it down.
How can he dare to sink my ship?
He is preparing to siege
Constantinople, your Grace.
Blocking our trade means
a war against us, too.
But we can't fight him directly.
We should better supply
support for Constantine.
I can go there with our ships and
command Constantine's army, your Grace.
Make your preparations right away.
Yes, your Grace.
Genoeses needed their trade route...
to be blocked to
come to their senses.
They will bring reinforcement, too.
And you, my dear lsidor.
I am sure you can arrange
Catholics and Orthodoxies...
pray together in church.
If you can achieve it...
I can provide more
reinforcements to save the city.
I will send a huge army of
archers with you to Constantinople.
The city has to trust you...
for us to succeed.
May God bless you.
I was worried that I wouldn't be
able to build what I designed...
when I decided not
to cast cannons any more.
But now...
I am glad you convinced me.
I know you did it for me, father.
Let me check the designs one more time.
Alright, father.
I am so grateful to the Pope.
Your existence brings high spirits
to my people and power to my army.
It is obvious that you
need more, your majesty.
If you want the support of Latin
governments against the infidel Turks...
you know what you have to do.
As Pope himself insists...
Orthodox people should
accept Vatican's authority.
It shouldn't be hard for a mighty
emperor like yourself to silence Gennadius
We will do what needs to be done.
My dear people.
How can a emperor who seeks salvation
from the Pope defend our faith?
And what is our patriarch doing?
He is selling our
religion in Hagia Sophia...
instead of giving us strength.
He accepts to pray...
in Catholics' way.
Instead of our own.
They want to make Orthodox people...
the slaves of the Catholic church.
Will you allow that?
Damn with the Patriarch.
There he is!
Get out of my way.
Please consider...
your decision one
more time, my Sultan.
We know that the Pope
has sent an archer legion.
And we are informed that...
Venetians and Genoeses will
provide troops and galleys.
It is obvious that Germans...
Englishmen and Frenchmen are
going to send huge reinforcements.
English and French armies...
destroyed each other.
The German King...
is busy with his own inner conﬂicts
Aren't you supposed
to know what is going
on in Europe better
than all of us, Mentor?
I heard enough of your
opposition in this matter.
My decision is final.
You should...
better realize that the siege is
better for your own interests, too.
Otherwise...
Zaganos.
Tell our spies to contact Gennadius.
Let them know that we guarantee...
their freedom of prayers
without any Catholic pressure.
And talk to Urban.
That cannon must be
finished as soon as possible.
We will start the
campaign in two months.
Yes, my Sultan.
After all that dust and mud,
this place is great for a change.
Thank you, Hasan.
I bet you have never eaten
such a delicious fish.
It smells great.
I added some ginger and laurel leaves.
I learnt it from my father.
You have never talked about your family.
My mother died when I was very young.
My father was a great warrior.
We went to Battle of Kosovo together.
He became martyr there.
Wanna taste it?
It is delicious.
It's a good thing that
I learnt the secret.
So you teach me to make
cannons and we get even.
You can't learn it right away.
It is an art.
This is the fourth time.
The metal is not pure
enough. It has veins.
I don't know why you object it?
We should include more tin.
That makes the solution denser. It will
congeal before it reaches the mould.
We can empower the fire.
It is powerful enough.
The next step is hell fire.
Why don't we give it a try? The
crucibles can endure more heat.
No. It is too risky.
You say no to everything.
Dear Giovanni Longo Di Giustiniani.
Your majesty.
You came here to help us against
the unbelievable of fences...
of the infidel army.
You and your heroic soldiers...
are worth more than anything for us.
Of course, we are
grateful for their support.
But there are also a
considerable number of people...
who haven't forgotten
the pain caused by...
the Latin armies, as well
as who greet them exuberantly.
Don't you think you are
unfair to soldiers...
who came to die for your
city, Grand Duke Notaras?
Our people...
will embrace these heroic soldiers...
who came to die for them, Notaras.
Never doubt that.
Maybe you are right.
We are almost out of copper, father.
I know. They will deliver it tomorrow.
Night shift is about to arrive, master.
You go and have a rest, Foreman
Mahmut. We will be staying.
Alright, master.
Why don't we leave
early today for a change?
I will make a delicious supper for you.
And I was wondering when you
were going to suggest this.
Please, father.
I know. Just help me take...
This is Notoras' business.
Thank you Hasan.
Seems like...
we won't rest until the walls fall.
Hasan.
What do you think, father?
I think we did it this time.
Thanks to you.
It's a good thing we signed a pact with
Hungarian, Serbian,
Polish and Georgian kings.
So we won't have any
problems during the siege.
They also thanked for the
beautiful presents you sent.
Good.
Halil Pasha saw that
he worried for nothing.
Are my warlords coming?
The cavalrymen of Karesi, Hamit and Mente?
Warlords will be in Edirne very soon.
What about the ships?
- They will be ready in time, my Sultan.
- Good.
(As I yearn to unite with my love)
(What is so natural than
my tears becoming a sea)
(You can't bring the beloved
to the house of sorrow, O Avni)
(No matter how strong your authority is)
Which perfume would you perefer to wear?
Jasmina.
He loves this the most.
I took...
this amulet from my
father when they killed him.
To give to my man if
I have one, one day.
I will never take it off.
Today is the big day.
I am very excited. You?
Me, too.
I don't want you to
be in the siege, Era.
You know I will. We talked about it.
I don't want you to get hurt.
I don't want you to get hurt, either.
So don't go to war, too.
War is not for women, Era.
Not for women, did you say?
You seem to forget what I went through.
They killed my mother
and sisters in the war.
None of them was a soldier.
They were slaughtered not in
the front line but at home.
Men die with honor in a war.
But women lose their
fathers, children...
husbands, honor, everything.
I will go to this war.
Nobody can stop me.
Kudos to all of you, Engineer Urban.
Thank you, my Sultan.
Have a safe trip.
I think you are right.
I was selfish. I am sorry.
We are going back.
CALLIPOLI
Allah is great!
You win. Well done, Mehmet.
Our Sultan!
Father.
Bayezid.
Come here.
Come here, son.
Father.
I wrote this for you.
My noble commanders...
brave soldiers...
and faithful people.
They dare to threaten...
our walls protected by our
guardian angel Mother Mary..
Who is not overwhelmed by anything.
Damn the Turks.
The infidel Turks are on their way...
to bite with their
poisonous fang of a snake.
They think they can
pass the most glorious...
and the strongest walls in history.
But we will drown them
in their own blood.
Death for the Turks.
You...
the children of Constantinople...
the queen city of the world...
I know that when the day comes...
you will all become fighters
worthy of St. Theodora...
and make another saga.
God is with us.
Damn the Turks!
You take the Pigi Gate, Nikola Mozenigo.
Cresca Gate. Commander Contarini,
deploy your troops there
Yes, your majesty.
Kaligaria Gate, John of Germania.
- Knight Guistiniani.
-  Yes, your majesty?
You will guard Romanos Gate
both with your own troops...
and the archers
Pope has sent with you.
This is our weakest point.
May God forbid, if Turks
happen to enter the city...
- ...you will be first to encounter them.
- Don't worry.
I will not allow even one
Turk to pass through that gate.
And our Turkish friend Orhan
will guard the Langa Port
Yes, your majesty.
May God protect our city.
EASTER APRIL 1, 1453
And you, Karaca Pasha.
This line from Gate of
Charisius to Ayvansaray is yours.
Yes, my Sultan
Sahabettin Pasha.
You take position from
Tekfur Palace to Egrikapi.
Yes, my Sultan.
Suleyman Pasha...
our navy must enter the Golden Horn.
It is the weakest point of the walls.
Yes, my Sultan.
Zaganos, you will hold the Galata ridge.
Hasan.
You will command the veteran soldiers.
Don't send the veterans or the cavalrymen
until we have a hole on the walls.
Yes, my Sultan.
You can leave now.
He tries to test our faith...
by starting the
siege in our holiest day.
But this will bring him the doom...
and bring us the salvation.
What shall we do, sir?
Are we going to sit and watch this war?
Are we going to trust
the Turkish promises?
Better than being
under Pope's authority.
But yet, we should do our
best to protect our city.
APRIL 6, 1453 FRIDAY
Guistiniani!
I'll tell you later.
'Selamun aleykum
"Kalos antamothsikame."
I wish I could have
hosted you in my palace...
but you are too crowded.
Thank you for the hospitality, Emperor.
I am here to host you in that palace.
I would like to remind you that...
our walls and our faith...
have never been
broken in history, Sultan.
You will never need to remind this
to anyone after this siege, Emperor.
My city walls heard this many times.
Last time was from your father.
But he couldn't succeed
either, just like the others.
We came here to conclude it.
If you give the city now, your
people and their families...
will keep living peacefully...
with their properties untouched.
Then, there will be a
lot of blood. Your blood.
We obeyed what Koran ordered.
Shutters!
Fire!
Come on!
Go, go. Take your place.
Shields!
Archers!
Shoot!
Basilica cannon.
You just couldn't get this Urban killed.
Archers!
Shoot!
Close this hole right now!
You, cover it with your arrows.
And you, bring the stones. Hurry.
Catapults!
Faster. Come on!
Burn it down. Kill them all!
Fill this gap!
Are you still thinking of Era, sir?
And Ayvansaray front?
The same, my Sultan.
We couldn't succeed in any of the lines.
We have heavy causalities, my Sultan.
We are trying to open the
Golden Horn front as you ordered.
But whenever we come
close to the chains...
long ranged Greek
cannons start firing.
Our soldiers should not wait.
They may think we are discouraged
because we're not fighting today.
That's exactly what I want
them to think, Zaganos.
Tell Head Sapper Mustafa to sap faster.
Tomorrow, they will know
why my soldiers are waiting.
Sir.
Report me.
We have enough oil and tar,
your majesty. Everything is fine.
There is no movement
in the Ottoman army.
They're trying to recover.
They saw what kind of
a hell they fell into.
We can't fire the Basilica
Cannon as frequent as we should.
If this foam works and
cools it down faster...
we can have 10 shots a day.
Era?
I'm dizzy.
I'm probably too tired.
We have 9 fathoms left, sir.
Good. I'll let the Sultan know.
Work harder, lions.
Almost there. Come on.
Get out. Now.
Run! Get out! It will collapse.
Get out! It will collapse.
Hurry, hurry, hurry. Run!
Selim.
Come on. Move.
Come on. Hurrry. Leave immediately.
- Run! Run!
-  We're coming.
Sappers.
They're here.
They're here. The sappers are here.
- Go back.
-  Come on, run.
Come here.
Dig it my lions. Dig it.
Faster.
Come on lions. Come on.
Jump in. Counter them.
Bring the gun powder barrels.
Come around, quick.
Come on sappers, dig it.
Stop. Silence.
Come on, faster. Come on. Come on.
They found us. Dig faster.
- Come on.
- Move it.
Come on, lions.
Come on.
They're very close.
Faster. Faster.
Come on lions, dig it.
- Sir, get out.
- Selim.
I won't leave you there, Selim.
They reached us. Leave us and go.
Faster. Come on.
It's too late. Just go, master.
Go now.
Forgive all my sins against you.
Run now.
Come on.
We will not die for nothing.
(I witness there is no God but Allah
And I witness Mohammed is
his servant and his Prophet.)
Allah is great.
- What's going on?
- Run.
- (Allah is great)
-  (Allah is great)
You summoned me, my Sultan.
One day while we were practicing
sword, you told me something, Hasan.
Using a sword needs skill.
You should not hold it
too tight or too loose.
If you hold it too tight, you get
tired right away, and can't move fast
If you hold it too loose, your
sword drops at the first impact.
Now is time to hold the
sword properly, Hasan.
It is your turn.
- Get ready.
-  Yes, my Sultan.
My Sultan gave his orders.
Tower siege assault is tonight
We will get ready.
Be careful, Hasan.
Archers!
- Archers!
- Shoot!
Break this door!
Kill these dogs.
Come on, hurry.
Faster.
I'm telling you, faster.
Fill these cauldrons. Fire
the cannons more frequently.
Come on.
Run! We need more archers here.
Burn those towers.
Fill these cauldrons. Come on.
Burn down those towers.
Get ready. Come on.
Faster.
Gangplank...
Brother!
Stay away!
Get ready to launch the gangplank.
Push the tower.
Put it.
We are in fire. We have to leave now.
Go away!
Faster.
Push it faster.
Burn them down. Don't
let them come closer.
Launch the gangplank.
Come on.
Move away.
Push it. Push it.
Come on. Fix the cannon.
Fire.
You are our heroes.
We'll bury them all, soon enough.
I saw Guistiniani on the walls.
You are right about him.
He is really a capable
and dangerous knight.
It could have been easier to pass
over the walls if he wasn't here.
Be careful with him, Hasan.
I checked all the fronts.
Our loss is not too much.
Especially when compared to Turks.
You were against the Latin
support, Grand Duke Notaras.
But as you see...
Turks are shattered everywhere.
The Pope should do more than this
to get rid of Mehmet for good.
We must catch his army between
the walls and the Crusaders.
Don't worry, your majesty.
Pope has already
convinced the Hungarians.
Leave him to us.
If I become a martyr
with Allah's will...
I'll ask a favor from you.
It is just an arrow. Don't
worry, it won't kill you.
Will you do it or not...
tell me that.
Tell me. What's that favor you'll ask?
You'll go and see...
my fiance.
Tell her that...
Huseyin became a
martyr with my honor.
Get well soon.
You will tell your fiance how you
fought after we break the walls.
I am Ladislaus, King of Hungary.
My long-running regent
John Hunyadi has been
relinquished from his
regency by my will.
I inform you that the truce you
signed with him is invalid...
and I salute you sincerely
with my belief that...
you will stop the
siege as soon as possible.
Please don't forget the great pain...
we both experienced
when our armies clashed.
Tell your king that I will
be happy to greet him...
here with my army.
My Sultan...
I always told you that
this campaign was a mistake.
We have been here for a month.
Our army is worn out.
If the Hungarians come...
This is just a threat, mentor.
Even if it is for real...
we will capture the city
before they arrive here.
If we can't, we will fight
with both Greeks and Hungarians
Now go...
and tell Urban that I want him
to fire his cannons more frequently.
Yes, my Sultan.
- Send more archers to the Pigi gate.
- Yes, your majesty.
Your majesty.
King of Hungary kept his promise.
- His envoy gave his message to Mehmet.
- Good.
When the Hungarians arrive, we
will not only defend our city...
but also get rid
of the Turks forever.
What do you think? Do you think
we should fire it more frequently?
Don't worry, father. My foam will work.
Alright.
- Foreman Mahmut, put the powder in.
-  Yes, sir.
Bring some more foam for
the next shot, daughter.
Stretch it, guys.
Father!
- Master? Master.
-  Move away.
- Father, open your eyes.
- Fetch the doctor.
It is all my fault.
What if he died?
Our sultan.
As you were.
When will he be okay?
In a few days, my Sultan.
Basilica Cannon has to be fixed.
- He must get well as soon as possible.
- Yes, my Sultan.
Don't worry.
I will fix the Basilica Cannon.
Move away.
Release some of these...
so it will motivate the Turks
I wish we were dead.
Move.
Take him.
Hey! Brave Turkish soldier.
You must have missed your friends here.
You believe that...
you go to heaven if
you die in war field.
Then, let's not keep you waiting.
I witness that there's
no god but Allah and I...
Stop those ships
Stop them. Stop them.
- My sultan.
-  Stop them.
Sink them, sink them!
My Sultan.
That's enough.
Thank God, we devastated his armada.
Let's see what you will do now, Mehmet.
For our emperor.
Long live our Emperor.
Long live Constantine.
You just couldn't stop 3 ships.
You haven't past over
the chains for 40 days.
But my Sultan, the range of
their cannons prevents us from...
Take him out.
Send to exile. Out, all of you.
Why aren't we fighting?
I was against this campaign
all from the beginning.
I said it would be our end.
Now look what we got.
You confused our Sultan.
Our government is at the verge of falling
because of your personal ambitions.
Our personal ambition is
to serve our government.
Is this your idea of serving?
Everybody knows your desire
is to get my position.
And you count on this campaign for that.
You have personal
interest on this conquest.
Why don't we all keep calm? We should
not forget about the Hungarian menace.
If they come to help
and they might already be on their way...
we are all doomed.
We should tell our Sultan that...
we must immediately cease the
campaign and go back to Edirne.
I hope you will be beheaded.
The Hungarian army gas gathered.
They will be here any time.
That's right.
If they come, we all die.
Our Sultan does not leave his pavilion.
Our Sultan is blinded. We can't pass
over the walls, no matter what we do.
We will die for nothing.
We should go back.
Why do you whine like a pussy?
Bastards!
Why do you eat our Sultan's bread?
No blood has spilled
from your sword for years.
Now our Sultan has opened a path to
glory for you. Is this why you treason?
Isn't it enough that we have been
fighting for 40 days for nothing.
Shut up!
Do you think a bunch of dogs
like you can start a mutiny?
Watch your words. If there
is a dog here, it must be you.
Now, go away.
Why doesn't he go back?
He can't accept his defeat.
I prefer him to be here
when the Hungarians arrive.
I will clean my boots with his robe.
Welcome, White Sheik.
We just had to call you.
He doesn't speak to anyone including us.
- Is he in his pavilion?
-  Yes, Master White Semsettin.
He hasn't gone out for two days.
Soldiers are restless.
My Sheik.
Welcome.
Thank you, Mehmet.
What's wrong with you?
Why doesn't your army fight?
We have been here for 40 days
Patience is the second mind to men.
It keeps your dream, your purpose alive.
I know, the unsuccessful attempts...
have caused disappointment
in both your army and you.
It discouraged your soldiers.
And the infidels are celebrating.
Come on Mehmet.
Come with me.
Before I came here...
slept for a vision for
three nights consecutively.
Just to see if this campaign
is destined good or bad.
Thanks God, I got what
I asked for last night.
I saw Hazreti Eyyubi Ensari in my dream.
He told me where his grave is
He said "Go. Show it to Mehmet."
Tell him why I am buried
so close to the walls.
My Sultan.
With the name of Allah
who protects and forgives.
As you know, Hazreti Eyyupjoined
the siege of Konstaniyyah...
with the Moslem army.
He didn't leave the city walls...
until he died.
And he wasn't young like you.
He was old and ill
You can't give up, Mehmet.
You came here...
to be that heralded commander.
Now go and lead your army.
If you don't do it now...
you'll never be able to do it again.
Now come back to your senses...
and show everyone
your superior skills.
You have the power to do this.
Remember...
strong winds wuther
at steep mountains.
I won't go back...
before I take this city, father.
MY leg!
MY leg! My leg is torn!
Come on, plankmen, run.
Hold the ropes.
Chock the ship.
They have hauled the ships on
the land to the Golden Horn.
Listen people.
They have hauled the ships on
the land to the Golden Horn.
Show mercy, mighty Lord.
Just when he thought he
would accept the defeat...
Our people and the army
are worried, your majesty.
This is no good.
He is trying to capture Golden Horn
where the city walls are the weakest.
He opened another front.
Our ships tried to sink them...
but they fire cannons from
Galata to keep us out of range.
We have to send troops to Golden Horn.
They don't have cannons in their
galleys. If we deploy troops there...
other fronts will get weaker
He will make a bridge of
ships to deploy in Golden Horn.
That's his plan.
Those Hungarians just couldn't come.
Guistiniani.
Send reinforcement to the Golden Horn.
Notaras...
go find Gennadius.
Tell him to do everything
to keep the high spirits
Oh Lord, you save us.
Our emperor asks a favor from you.
A man who subdues Pope
can't be my emperor.
For God's sake.
You know I feel the same.
But you have to help us
in these troubled days.
People are in terror. There is chaos.
You think I don't know this?
You should use your
influence on the people.
I'm already doing that despite of you.
But you sold Orthodox
people to the Catholics.
And after all those holy signs...
the faith in our people...
is gone just like the
light in Hagia Sophia.
People are desperate.
My soldiers.
We have a glorious history.
We conquered many
strong forts and cities.
We passed high mountains.
We broke the javelins...
which our enemies
hold against our chests.
We teared down the enemy ﬂags
which were planted in vanity.
We died and suffered
for the sake of glow.
Today...
it is our duty...
to prove that we are
worthy of our forefathers.
Remember!
Glow is achieved with faith.
I know we will pass over
these walls with our courage
Tomorrow...
we will wake up for a happy morning
no other God's servant has seen.
We won't become martyrizes...
before we bring our
enemies to their kneels.
God is great!
I was looking for you.
We will achieve victory tomorrow.
You will see, we will do it.
And your evenge will be taken, Era
Hasan.
MAY 29,1453 TUESDAY
Today...
he will try his strongest assault.
If we can fend it off...
this war will finish.
Don't worry. Your people
will celebrate your victory.
That's all of it, sir.
You couldn't find us
this time, the reptiles.
Sir, I am pouring the
powder to the exit.
Sir?
I don't want any mistakes.
Cabuk cikin.
Fire!
Attack!
They broke down the wall!
- Run.
-  They got in.
They broke down the Romanos wall, your
majesty. You have to get out of here.
We have to go back to the palace.
You should stay in a safe
place until we repel them.
Remember you told me...
to tell your fiancé.
And you go to my family...
I will.
I will let them know you became
an martyr with your honor.
HuSeyin!
To the ﬂag tower.
You will have a painful death...
but nobody will know it.
History don't tell about the losers
We never forget the martyrs.
But today you will die and
nobody will remember you.
Run. Go to Hagia Sophia.
People and the army...
believe that our
God given holy light...
is taken back to Heaven.
You have to leave the
city, your majesty.
Our holy light...
was taken to Heaven long ago.
At least I should fight...
for my honor to the end.
Your emperor is dead.
You are under arrest.
Long live the Sultan.
Stand up.
Bury your emperor due to your religion.
Don't worry.
From now on, your lives...
your property...
and your destiny
are a part of us, too.
You are free to live
according to your own faith.