Our Mothers, our Fathers
Episode 3: A different country
Wilhelm
Charlotte
"Most people think,
that war mainly consists of fighting."
"But that's not true.
It's waiting..."
"...for the next attack,
the next meal,
the next morning."
Erika.
Stop here.
Is he dead?
- No idea.
No.
Do you speak german?
Yes.
Are you german?
Shit. Untether him.
What now? How long do you want to wait?
Until we know on which side your friend is.
Who was that?
Partisans.
We'll take you with us.
No.
We don't leave you behind...
We stay here. We three.
If you lay down your weapons,
maybe they'll let you live.
There are ten heavily armed
Partisans over there.
He's warning them.
Shoot!
Shit. It's an ambush.
Shit. Shit. Shit. Shit.
Shoot!
I said: Shoot!
It's jammed!
Shit, what are you doing...
What's going on?
Andrej, Marek... Move! Quick!
Once again, two of them less!
Be quiet! Better collect these rounds...
Watches, rings, golden teeth...
Not bad. Not bad, Kiddo!
Not bad! I like you, Kiddo!
You really wanted to shoot, didn't you?
Winter, get out!
There are still a few...
...who think they can just
chicken out of the lifestruggle
of the German Empire.
Your verdict was changed.
The Fuhrer has approved
a special parole for you.
And from now on...
...you belong to me,
the Bewährungsbataillon 500.
To weed out all the trash:
Defeatists, Communists,
Deserteurs...
I guess the Fuhrer needs
every man for the final victory?
We're not wasting bullets on
scumbags like you.
You still are going to die.
Just a little slower.
And before you die you can do
something for your german fatherland.
Stand up, we're leaving!
"Most people think,
War consists mostly of fighting."
"That's not true."
Mount up!
"It's waiting..."
"June 1944. I don't know if my
brother Friedhelm is still alive."
"And the others,
Greta, Viktor, Charly."
"150.000 Americans
have landed in the Normandy."
"Rome has fallen. The Wehrmacht
has evacuated Tuscany."
"Three years ago we took off,
to save our people,
as we thought."
"But instead, we have brought
death, suffering and destruction upon millions."
"Back then we were heroes,
today we are murderers."
We need Butter, Flour, Milk, Eggs.
Something else?
Pigs. -
Pigs. At least three a month.
And geese? For christmas?
The germans just go and take them...
We pay.
After each of your activities,
the germans take hostages.
And when the Russians come,
it won't get better.
Show me your arm.
Come on, show me!
Just raise it like that!
Is that better?
Do you want it to be like this?
The Russians are coming.
No matter what happens.
Stalin will defeat Hitler.
He has defeated him at Stalingrad
and Kursk
The Germans think of us as slaves.
But the russians do so as well.
Are we really? Slaves?
Are there any jews among you?
Jews?
Are here any?
Are there any Jews present?
No, no Jews. I can smell Jews.
Three bags of flour...
...fifty Eggs and four Chickens.
- Ten.
Eight.
All right. Eight.
And no Jews.
We drown Jews like cats.
You're with Erika in cell 17.
What's your name?
Greta.
Is it true that you used to be a singer?
The women say,
you were Greta DelTorres.
Winter. Ever driven a
PKW Typ 40?
Good. Tomorrow Standartenführer
Hiemer is arriving here.
He's leading the mission
against the polish partisans.
He needs a driver, who is familiar with the
surroundings.
Can you take care of that?
- Yes.
Good.
You there! Come with me!
You see that hut?
It's in the artilleries line
of fire. Burn it.
Jawohl.
That's idiotic.
What was that?
The fire will alert the Russians.
You are going to burn that
Bolshevik-Hut there now.
Three years ago they welcomed us
as liberators.
Burn it!
If god doesn't grand us victory,
we're all going to pay.
Whatever god's intention is,
it most certainly isn't victory.
Tschai?
Please sit down.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
You're lucky. It's healing well.
In three or four days
you can be discharged.
How many days of
convalescent leave do I get?
What's going on? Does that mean
vacations are banned?
Treatment as before.
Nurse?
Weird.
I can't smell anything burnt.
That's insubordination!
And you know, what's the penalty for that.
Herr Oberfeldwebel!
Herr Oberfeldwebel! Staff is calling!
What!?
- We're not allowed to lay fires.
Otherwise the russians will know
we're retreating.
Attention!
Do you have something for me?
Hiemer.
He lead the fights against
the jews and partisans.
In the Ukraine and Belarus.
Thorough and cruel.
He is going to come here because of us.
Prepare everything. We're going to attack tomorrow.
Stalin will be victorious.
Try to sleep.
Hans!
Nurse Char...
Psst...!
What...?
Do you want to go back to the frontlines?
But the doctor said...
Bite this!
Don't make a sound!
Psst...!
We should...?
What are you doing there?
Nothing! Go away!
That'll get you two weeks.
Then convalescent leave at the
military hospital in Berchtesgaden.
Go.
What's going on here Gefreiter?
Partisans have destroyed
the bridge right ahead.
The Standartenführer has to turn left
here and after 3km right again and then
continue the regular route.
What is that supposed to be?
How did you know that there
was an ambush?
Instinct.
- Instinct, yeah?
I guess, you're experienced after all.
Yes.
I instantly recognized you.
I never forget a face.
I've even got your file sent for me.
You have a brother.
Wilhelm.
- He is dead.
Desertion.
He isn't dead.
He was pardoned.
Bewährungsbataillon 500.
Shall we drive?
I just...
Please. Sit down.
Your name is Sonja.
Yes.
What are you reading?
"The enlightenment of a hunter."
What is it about?
It's about the poor under Tsar Nicholas.
They are slaves. The lords do with them
whatever they want.
Buy, sell.
Wassja is a farmers boy.
His lord beating him.
We treat our own people so bad.
We germans can do that as well.
I once knew someone. She was...
Hey, you there! Empty the bedpans!
What's going on with you?
Do you really think I don't
see what you're doing?
The private on the A,
and the others?
Are you mad?
That's undermining of military morale.
I'm supposed to report you.
Do you think the Russians will spare you,
if they win?
I thought, you were firmly
believing in the final victory.
What else?
The Russians are breaking through everywhere.
Minsk already has fallen.
It's just 500 km to warsaw.
When we lose the war,
do you know what they're doing to us?
Huh?
Get down! Down!
Damn it,
don't shoot unless ordered to!
Way too nervous.
Oh, ho. Rabbit hunt.
There you go. Your rabbit.
On Three.
One...
two...
Woman screams
Bring them to the city!
Each and every cowardly attack
on soldiers of the german Wehrmacht
by criminal and malicious gangs
will also in the future
be met with relentless retaliation.
As a warning for everyone,
who is involved or is planning to be.
Understood?
Give me that.
Friedhelm. Come on!
On my command.
And... now!
They were our friends!
You're right.
But now?
What kind of alternative do you have?
Agnieszka had two little children.
So, Stanisu, do you have any idea?
I'm asking you a question!
Do you want to lay down your arms?
But because of us Poles are dying!
- Because of us?
How because of us?
Do you personally put a noose
around their necks?
Does Krystyna slit their throats?
Krystyna, do you slit their throats?
One of them was Agnieszka.
We knew them all!
If they want to kill us,
it means we have to kill them.
Until Poland is free again.
Shut up!
- Quiet!
Stop it! Not a single word now!
It's not about dying,
it's about how we die.
Did you hear that?
And that from the german twat.
Good, Victor!
We'll just manage with the Russians...
but if the Germans win the war,
we'll all be sentenced to death.
What...?
A transfer?
You can go back to Germany with this.
I...
I'm supposed to turn my back on all of you here?
The war is almost over. Maybe only a few months...
You... you could wait for me there.
Hildegard wanted to report you.
You're sabotaging the
recovery of soldiers.
That is undermining of military morale.
Bewährungsbataillon.
Cowards and traitors.
We should stay away from them.
Do I belong to them as well?
I warned you.
You're denouncing me!?
I'm just doing my duty.
Like you did with Lilija.
Wilhelm.
You know one of those?
Charly!
No!
I don't understand.
Friedhelm said you were...
I know.
Come here!
It's okay.
No! You have to be dead.
You have to be dead!
All this time I have...
I love you...
Charly!
Don't worry nurse,
he's going to die soon.
Charly!
Wilhelm!
Here, eat!
Eat it! Regardless of how disgusting it is.
Just like Arthur here.
You were good.
Do you know, that I met my
husband because of you?
I took the train to Bernau
with a couple of girls.
We hiked to the Liepnitzsee.
In the evening there was a dance
at the beer garden.
And they played your song there.
He kept looking at us
He was large, pretty good looking.
and when he came to us,
I thought at first he meant Inge.
But he asked me.
He kept dragging his right leg,
the SA had smashed it.
But he danced well.
I knew it from this evening on,
that he was the one.
We married after two months.
And tomorrow morning,
they are going to pick me up.
"... you're my husband"
"My tiny heart"
"Doesn't stay still"
"It keeps me awake the whole night"
"and just keeps beating..."
"July 1944.
We're back where we started three years ago.
"The Heeresgruppe Mitte
was worn down. A half million soldiers."
"The red army is
at the Vistula."
"Soon, Warsaw will fall."
"The war is long lost."
"But he doesn't stop."
"My brother was right."
"We're cattle
in a large slaughterhouse."
A gang of cowardly
traitors to the fatherland
has attempted an assasination
of the Fuhrer.
But there is a vision
for germany.
Which is called: Adolf Hitler.
The Fuhrer lives.
Is there anyone here,
who is extraordinarily dissappointed!?
With him, we'll never give up.
We'll fight for every city,
and for every house until the end.
We've got to hurry up then.
An order
is inviolable for a German.
In the last war,
we haven't given up as well.
It was the jews back home,
who have betrayed the army.
But this time,
this won't happen to us.
You collect the dead!
"German soldiers."
"The war is lost. Hitler and
his generals have lied to us."
"I was a soldier as well."
"Oberst Brandlmeier
of the 11th Infantry division."
"I have fought bravely and
honorably for four years,
until I realized that we
were betrayed.
"The red army will defeat germany."
"But Stalin is reaching us his hand."
"Throw away your guns and come to us"
"The Russians are not subhumans,
as they told us."
"They guarantee an honorable treatment."
"Three meals and being able to return to your
home to children and wifes right after the war." No way.
(Music: Giuseppe Verdi -
"Chorus of the slaves")
Good luck.
Good!
It's possible that the military hospital
is going to be moved again.
What are you going to do then?
Come with us?
Then they will...
...as a traitor.
I couldn't get closer.
Most of them are women. Jews.
They produce Ammunition packaging
for the Wehrmacht and mend uniforms.
This is our target. The weapons depot.
There are four watch towers with searchlights.
That fence is live. Very deadly.
Sometimes prisoners to run into it
if can't handle it anymore.
The guards are ukranian SS.
We can't go in at the front.
What's that?
The train supplies them with
food and weapons.
When it's empty, it transports the
Ammo Packaging and the uniforms for the Wehrmacht.
We're attacking on open ground.
You find out when the next
transport is due.
Do you understand?
We attack train.
Take care of Arthur.
You can take pork...
...or beef...
...or deer...
That's so good.
No, the most important is the sausage.
With garlic.
and Sauerkraut.
Mushrooms and Sauerkraut.
It doesn't matter what you put in a 'Bigos'.
You have to let it sit
for at least one night.
My grandmather kept saying:
"A good 'Bigos' is like a good marriage.
The longer it takes,
the longer it tastes."
What you saying?
Since when does a German know
what 'Bigos' is?
Soundy like a Goulashe.
Goulashe?
Bigos is no Goulashe.
Bigos is Poland.
You said the train will be here at nine.
Yes. So?
Am I responsible for the Germans?
Maybe they already capitulated.
And what if he ignores the stop signal
and keeps driving?
He won't do that.
A german officer doesn't
ignore a german sign.
Not yet...
Now.
Now!
Stop!
I think we killed them all.
The first group comes with me.
Stop!
Where the hell did that come from?
There's one left!
Did we get him?
On Three? One...
...two, three.
Go!
What are we doing with them?
What do you mean?
Most of them are Jews.
Jews are as bad as
communists and russians.
Better dead than alive.
They shall die?
- Yes.
Here. Move!
Come on, get out!
Out.
Run!
What are we going to do with the jew?
Leave him to me, you got it!?
Herr Standartenführer. There was
a series of attacks in the outbacks.
What else?
New reports keep coming in.
50 bridges and 150km of track.
- We'll start a raid tomorrow.
There was a hint from the civilians.
Prepare everything!
Get dressed!
Stop!
I had this feeling from the very beginning
The others said:
He is one, he looks like one.
Yes, Viktor. Now I know it.
You're a German...
...and a Jew.
You were a good comrade.
But now I can't help you anymore.
Go!
Viktor!
The war won't take much longer.
I wish you luck,
so you survive it.
[Door opens]
Leave us alone!
Greta DelTorres.
3246.
What do you want?
I want you to sign this.
That I helped your jewish friend.
Does it look so bad,
that you need a jew now?
Why, do you think it is,
that you're still alive?
And you can stay alive.
What kind of feeling is it,
to know, that he left you alone
and is now safe in New York?
A good one.
Don't think they'll save you!
Before even a single ally arrives here,
you'll all be gone.
This was the last time.
We'll never meet again.
Get away, as long as you can.
Have you heard anything about my parents?
How should I know, get lost!
The others? Greta?
Go!
What about her?
Arrested. Are you deaf!?
Bugger off!
Arrested?
Why? Why?
Defeatism.
Defeatism? Greta?
That's impossible.
Watch out Friedhelm!
On three, okay?
One...Two...
Run away.
You won't get a second chance.
What about you? The war is lost.
It's pointless.
It was from the very beginning.
"February 1945. The red army
crossed the Oder."
"Now it's less than 100km to Berlin."
"The war won't last much longer."
"I'm just scared that the hope returns,
this close to the end.
Russians!
Get down!
What do we do now?
Hurry up!
This scumbag wants us to die here.
What's his name?
I don't know.
He just arrived this morning.
Go!
Spreader.
Tweezers!
The Russians have broken through
across the board.
Pad!
They are just 5 km away from here.
Stitch up, and put braces on.
But...
Evacuate everything! Now!
What about those who can't be transported?
They stay here.
(Goebbels) "That our soldiers,
when they take on the offense
at the eastern front,
won't know any pardon,
and won't give a quarter."
"...who have already started
smaller attacks,
will in the next weeks and months
take on large-scale offenses."
"Those who can't come with us,
get Morphium." Good.
Sonja!
"...will go into this battle
like going to mass."
"When they shoulder their rifles
and mount their armored cars,
they only have their slain childr..."
Sonja?
Have you seen Sonja?
The russian nurse? No.
The Russian! We can't wait no longer.
Where is Sonja?
No idea.
The Russians are only 500m away.
Sonja!
Charlotte!
Come on! Faster!
We're departing now.
Sonja?
Nurse!
The Russians...
Please.
Take them!
What's your name?
- Sonja Michailowa.
Sonja!
No, please don't!
We're soviet soldiers!
Liberators - not rapists.
Get out of here,
if you don't want me to shoot you!
Lilija. Thanks
Go away!
All of you!
Sonja!
What happens to her?
She is a traitor.
Go!
Breslau ist surrounded.
We should try to...
Watch out. He's on the lookout.
Get lost.
What?
Get lost!
How many lives
does a scumbag like you have?
I have only one left.
I wanted to bid farewell.
Do you know,
what I'm going to do to you?
My war is over.
And yours is as well.
Come on! Help out here.
And now get lost!
You haven't seen anything.
They won't believe me anyway.
"This is the BBC home service."
"Here is the news read by Frederic Dryfuss."
"We begin
by taking listeners over direct
to one of our transmitters in Germany
were Frank Gillard is waiting to speak..."
Martin, please. Hurry up!
Military police.
We'll wait until it's dark.
She is a nurse.
She can take care of our wounded.
She can atone for her sins.
In a few weeks we have won the war.
With whom else
shall we build a better germany?
The nurse... ?
Charly...
How likely is it, as a soldier,
to return home alive?
So I just thought...
To save her the pain?
Us.
Did you count them...
...the ones you've killed?
No.
Twelve. I have killed twelve.
And saved none..
In the beginning you were a hero,
now you're just a bastard.
It was quicker for her that way.
She was sentenced to death.
And why do you help me?
Because it would just go on like this.
See you in Berlin.
Did you think we forgot you?
Ten-hut! Aim!
Fire!
Wilhelm!
That's my direction.
Farewell!
Farewell.
"May 1945."
"Four years ago,
we bid farewell."
"We were five friends
who thought,
the war would be over by christmas."
"Now it ends
where it began."
"In Berlin."
"Or what's left of it."
"Soon there will only be Germans,
and not a single Nazi."
"And who will we be?"
Yeah?
Hey 'here!
What's that s'pposed to be?
What are you doin' in ma apartmend?
Your apartment?
Yes.
Was it always yours?
Yeah. Why shouldn' it?
Really?
Well, supposedly,
Jews used to live here
but 'hey have moved away.
Hey, 'hat's enough!
Yeah, I kept 'hat.
It's not like I ever had anything against 'hem.
I always tried to help 'hem.
Those... Jews.
Cover!
Cease fire!
Cease fire, goddamnit!
You dumb fucks...
Germans surrender!
The war is over!
"The German soldiers should give up.
War ees over."
These bastards are lying.
That's just propaganda.
If we surrender,
they'll just shoot us.
The Fuhrer has promised us that we will win.
- We still have rounds left.
How could we look into the
eyes of your mothers if we surrender?
Just be glad you can look
her in the eyes at all!
You... You're an old, spineless coward!
How old are you?
- Twelve.
You're children.
The Russians will send you home.
Please send this
to the adress on the back.
He's attacking them.
Next!
Next please.
Next please!
The Police and the administration
are looking for experienced staff.
Do you have any experience?
Oh yes, quite a lot.
But not as much as you,
Sturmbannführer.
Do we know each other?
To think that you
work at German administration...
My experience is needed.
Twelve years experience
in torturing and killing?
Please help me, I can't remember everyone.
Captain.
This is Sturmbannführer Dorn
from the Gestapo.
You know that?
What happened to Greta?
Viktor Goldstein.
I've provided you with papers.
I provided this man with papers
so he could flee to Marseille.
Greta, yeah.
It's a real shame.
I tried everything to save her.
Even I have almost lost my family.
It's nice that you have survived.
Next.
(Sign: "Dancing to Swing is prohibited")
We don't have to wait for Friedhelm.
Fallen, for Fuhrer,
People and Fatherland.
Anyone heard anything from Greta?
It's good you're alive.
To Friedhelm and Greta!