Our mothers, our fathers
Episode 2: Another war
"May 1943. Two years ago we said
farewell in Berlin."
"Two years and no end in sight.
At first it was just a new feeling."
"But . The German Wehrmacht
isn't invincible."
"We took up position at Orel.
They say that there will be a last decisive battle."
"The battle,
that will end war."
"I don't know if I can still fullfill
the expectations of my men:
the firm believe in victory."
Lets go.
Cover!
Get out!
Scared us quite much.
Nurse, please help me!
Nurse. A pressure bandage for the russian.
But we aren't allowed to...
Just do it.
Head wound first.
What about the russian?
We don't even have enough morphium
for our own men.
Crank up the radio, Nurse Charlotte.
Nurse Hildegard, you assist.
(Vocals) "My tiny heart
craves after you."
"And the answer, when you ask me:
Yes, I belong to to you."
"Yes, I...
belong to you."
That was the famous singer
Greta DelTorres
with "My tiny heart".
The high command of the Wehrmacht
announces:
The Fuhrer advices from the
Fuhrerheadquarters...
I thought the Obersturmbannführer
wanted to...
I'm sorry, Miss Greta.
As far as I know he visits the opera with
his wife.
With his wife.
Get out! Faster! Go on, chop-chop!
Drive me home.
3 days until the battle of Kursk
(Soldier singing)
"All will be gone."
"Two years in russia and not ponimaij."
Get yourself some food.
- Jawohl.
Jawohl.
- Yes.
Fresh out of basic.
Half children.
The older the war,
the younger the soldiers.
What about my holiday?
The Oberleutnant said, that all holidays
are cancelled. We need every man to prepare
the offensive.
Shit. My fiancee...
- You don't even have a fiancee, Bartel.
How should I get one without holiday?
Hello. If I'm allowed to introduce myself,
my name...
What was the name of the red head last week,
Schneider?
The one, whose head was blown off by a grenade.
- (stutters) Boom!
If you are still alive in four weeks you can
tell me your name.
And till then: One, Two.
Your brother will make men out of them.
Yeah, sure.
Nurse, what's your name?
Charlotte.
Do want to drink a bit with me?
I'm not drinking while on duty.
Then give me a kiss.
Today is my birthday, my 21st.
Happy Birthday then.
The shrapnels in my head are moving.
It's inoperable.
I must look like a ghost.
That's funny
because we're from the 707th.
they call us the Gespensterlegion.
Gespensterlegion? Why is that?
Because we make the jews disappear.
Even women?
What do you think, what happened to Lilija?
She was a good Nurse.
Listen, she was jewish.
And the jews want our demise, right?
Watch out that something like that
isn't overheard by the wrong people.
No knocking?
Do you think that I'm one of your
BDM-Bunnies?
I could have been naked.
There is nothing I don't know yet.
Tyke!
Does your wife have a migraine again?
Maybe we should meet each other
over a cup of coffee.
You should have called.
I didn't have time.
I need to learn the new songs.
You will need to learn a lot more of them.
What do you think about a tour?
A... tour?
Some dancers, a juggler.
And the main feature: Greta DelTorres.
I could ask Marika Rökk instead.
I could learn some french chansons.
I always wanted to visit the Moulin Rouge.
You will visit Paris afterwards.
Afterwards?
The tour goes east.
Ah.
Warsaw.
Uh well, I could also...
Russia.
What? You don't believe that...
You will sing in front of hundred of soldiers.
Dirty, smelly... officers,
that haven't seen women for a long time.
You will celebrate a triumph.
And after the victory: Paris.
Milan.
Rome.
Vienna.
Budapest.
All of Europe will stand open for you.
You should pack.
Tomorrow your plane will start.
What are our chances?
The german Afrikakorps has surrendered.
It's only 300 kilometer from Tunis to Sicily.
And after that the allies will attack Italy.
We need to fend off the Russian.
Excuse me, Herr Oberleutnant.
When are we finally going to fight?
Will the Russians attack us?
- Of course we will attack first.
The german will allways attack first.
The Fuhrer says, that the war will
be decided till winter.
Did he mention the year as well?
- That's undermining of military morale.
Defeatism.
- Mhm.
Okay boys, it's late, Curfew.
Good night, Herr Oberleutnant.
Go into the house kids, go!
Get away from the well!
Schneider! Away from the well!
Wait! Please stop!
Your flight will depart in 30 minutes.
I know.
Yes?
Excuse me, I might have...
Did ya wanna visit 'he jews?
Yes.
'hey 're gone.
Gone?
Berlin is free of jews now, remember?
'hey didn' even clean'd up the flat,
'hat dirdy plebs. You won' believ' it.
Shut it! Or 'he russian will come!
Ah, well. At least the furniture was
usable.
Say, do you 'ave somethin' to do with
'hose?
(Old man) What are you doing there?
Do you see that, she can't do that.
Stop it! They will shoot us all.
Stop the Train! Stop! Stop!
Hey! You dead. Maybe tomorrow or in a month
or in a year.
But scream again and you dead now.
That is apply to anyone.
Nobody need follow me, but nobody will stop me.
I was in Sachsenhausen.
They said they need workers for a plant in Lublin.
You are lucky.
Bon voyage then.
Is not strange that train depart always full
and return empty?
Come.
Gentlemen, now it's time. Our week-long
preparations will be finished soon.
Tomorrow our offensive will start with an
attack on the central russian front line,
that targets the front advance at Kursk.
The code name is: "Zitadelle".
The attack will be conducted starting from two
wedges starting at Orel und Bjelgorod.
East of Kursk we close the pincer
with Hoths 4th tank army.
This decisive battle will bring back the
initative to the german Wehrmacht.
Within six days Kursk must fall.
The Fuhrer expects every man to do his best.
This evening a famous singer will appear
to raise the troops morale.
The men should relax
one last time before it starts.
Thanks.
Oberleutnant Winter.
I'm sorry to hear about the assault
on your troops.
The assassins will be executed
at this very day of course.
What's going on, Wilhelm?
We already had entered the outer
district of moscow.
And now it's more than 500 kilometer again.
I know, Stalingrad was a desaster.
But we still can win this war.
We reclaimed Charkow and Bjelgorod.
After we lost them.
PULL YOURSELF TOGETHER!
We need to win this battle.
That is the last chance to bleed out the Russians
before the Americans join in.
And now leave.
Herr Hauptmann.
"How do you lead your men into a battle,
that most of them won't survive?"
"The real victors of this war are the flies."
"We feed them with our flesh."
Ten-hut!
Ready!
Fire!
You chickenshit missed on purpose!
- I...
You're such a stupid coward.
Friedhelm.
Come.
What do you see?
No train station. No city.
Wait.
Tanks. Train full of tanks.
Listen.
Military train have priority.
If we lucky, german planning something in
east and give us time.
We need to rest.
- Minutes. Then we continue work.
"My tiny heart
only beats for you."
"It knows the answer,
when you ask me then:"
"Yes, I belong to you."
"Yes, I...
belong to you."
Thanks.
Hello?
Listen boys, if you think that...
Friedhelm!
Hello.
What a surprise!
Nice to see you again.
Charly!
You were wonderful.
Who'd have guessed that.
We need to celebrate that.
Ah! Wait... I have it with me.
We were so young.
What happened to Viktor?
It was for is passport. He left.
He is well. I visited his parents.
Champain.
The Fuhrer says, that at the
end of the year Germany will have won the war.
And then we four go to Milan and
Paris to my performances.
Here's to you, Greta.
Here's to you.
To us!
Knocking
Come in.
Ah, damn. The regiment commander
holds a private supper.
Coming!
Well then.
Take whatever you need.
And don't wait for me.
I believe it... will get late.
But I'm still here for a few days.
Well then, lets celebrate
Greta DelTorres in absense.
Exactly. Yes.
I need to go too.
Hauptmann Feigl expects me.
Yeah.
I need to go too, then.
Come on, what's that all about?
We party a little bit. Hm?
Wilhelm, what about you? We haven't seen
each other in ages. Here, a Bordeaux.
34. Charly.
Why can't we...
My patients are waiting!
You're an asshole, do you know that?
I don't want to get her hopes up.
Your soldier with the head injury...
Yes?
Don't you feel well?
Here. What's with him?
He died.
Good.
Go!
Who is of brave come to us now.
I can't do that.
Herr Leutnant.
When we shot the peasants because of the well,
do you believe,
that all of them were partisans?
No.
Did you kill a lot?
You kill them before they kill you.
Easy as that.
I wanted to sign up
for the winter semester in Freiburg.
With Professor Heidegger.
Philosophy and history.
Do you believe... do you believe
that will work out?
Maybe you should go for
the summer semester instead.
Yeah, sure. My mother told...
- Shut up now.
Of course. Sorry.
One hour and 20 minutes.
What do you think?
It will be everyone's turn.
Schneider was killed behind the front line.
When he beat you up...
That was okay.
No, it wasn't.
I left you alone.
It is...
It isn't always easy to know what
is right.
Father always expected from me that, I...
Shell impacts.
Attack!
(Soldier) To arms!
Move! Move! Move!
Faster!
Spread out!
Cover!
Fuck, they are firing too short!
- These are not ours you retard!
I can't take it any more...
Prepare everything.
Hey!
Wake up.
Miss Müller, we need to go.
Shortly.
The pilot needs to start now.
Do you think I'm going to leave all of that behind?
- If you think so, Miss Müller.
Tell them they should wait.
I'm Greta DelTorres!
That are ours! Conk them, boys!
Eat Kruppstahl!
It's alright.
That happens to most of us at the beginning.
Let's get started.
Yes sir. Here we go! Stand up!
Here we go!
Come on, boys! Here we go!
Let's get startet!
The Russians know that we will
attack.
We won't surprise them.
I know.
Press firmly. You'll make it.
I need an Infusion!
Greta?
Hang on. You'll make it.
These idiots departed without me.
What's your name?
Werner.
Look at me!
I tried to call the commander, but to no avail.
You will be operated.
I thought you could help me, maybe?
What?
Nurse! Werner?
Werner.
I need a nurse!
Pick it up.
What?
Pick up!
Come on!
Count to three.
One, two, three.
The peasant calls something on polish.
Quick!
Rifle shots
Faster!
What are you planning to do?
No idea.
Going back to Germany. And you?
Warsaw.
Alina.
Viktor.
I not thought I tell this to German:
Keep alive!
Stop! Stop!
Run!
"July 7th, 1943."
"For three days the greatest tank
battle in the war has raved,
the one, which shall bring the decision."
"Over 7000 tanks face each other."
"Friedhelm was right.
The red army was prepared for our attack."
"The casualities were immense."
"We hope for reinforcements every day."
There is a telegraph station two kilometers
in this direction.
Your task is to claim and hold it,
together with the second platoon.
Will there be tank support?
- The resistance of the Russians is fierce.
We lost half of our tanks and forty percent
of the crews.
There is no support, since all reserves are
already engaged in combat.
You will capture and hold the station
under any circumstances.
No enemy movement.
We are here.
The telegraph station is located 300 meters
north east. This way.
The... the first-
The second squad takes the lead.
The first squad follows closely. Third squad stays
a bit behind to provide fire support.
Understood?
Jawohl, Herr Oberleutnant.
Lets go Ladies! March!
Lock and load.
Go, Go, Go, Go!
- (stutters) Come, you first.
To the passage.
First squad leads. Go!
Hey!
Grenade!
Bartel, on my command!
Covering Fire!
Go boy!
Advance!
Seibold, Winter, secure.
Move boy!
Stand up... Ahh!
Tank!
Get out!
Retreat!
How do you bear that?
You have changed.
You're so...
I killed a women.
Lilija. She was a jew.
She helped me,
and I betrayed her.
Nothing is like we imagined, Greta.
I hoped Viktor would write me.
I have no Idea how he is.
And where he is.
This wound won't heal by itself.
That's dangerous.
It needs to be stiched.
And?
Why did you end up in the train?
After our capitulation
your men did caught me on street.
and send me to Germany for work.
A farm in Franconia.
What happended?
Didn't you like it there with some
Eisbein and Sauerkraut?
And you? You're of Jew?
Maybe you undress in front of German.
Bite it.
Where is Oberleutnant Winter?
Where is the goddamn backup?
- Where are they?
They left us alone!
Herr Oberleutnant message from
Hauptmann Feigl.
The Russians started
an attack at Orel.
And the allies landed on Sicily.
There's your two front war.
They say, that the Fuhrer relocates
the II. SS-Panzerkorps to the west.
And the Luftwaffe doesn't have
enough fuel for air support.
We absolutely need backup here.
I'm sorry.
We can't reach Kursk under this conditions.
You should rest until tomorrow.
But your Order is still to
capture and hold the telegraph station.
All of Sicily is abandoned
and my men are being sacrificed
for a piece of street!
You're relieved.
You were right. It only brings out
the worst in all of us.
Yeah, I know.
But this doesn't change anything.
We will fight again tomorrow.
Until no one is left.
Exactly. Until no one is left.
How many we knew
fell in the last two years?
Schneider, Dogerlow,
Verbindsky, Bertok...
For no reason...
Stop it!
It will only stop when it has ended.
Don't you get it?!
We're just human cattle for the slaughterhouse!
Todays heros, tomorrows pigs.
But this doesn't make sense!
There is no sense!
God abandoned us!
There is only us!
No fucking general, no Fuhrer.
Just us, these men out there!
If we croak tomorrow then
so be it.
But you will lead us.
I expect this from you.
Two! Ammo!
Herr Oberleutnant!
Wilhelm!
Ah!
For that?
For that.
God!
For that! Ah!
We wait until it's get dark.
If our men don't get here we'll go back.
Maybe we have a chance.
How did you become like this?
You resist the temptation of being humane.
Some go this way, some the other.
Nobody knows.
But one thing is for sure:
nobody stays the way he was.
How did you survive that long?
You hope the one next to you is hit.
A good soldier is a coward most of the time
and sometimes brave.
Then you aren't a good soldier.
Keep your head down, okay?
The Russians have sibirian hunters, that
shoot a hole in a coin on 300 meters.
The German came to me every night.
His women acted as nothing happened.
Than I realized, I...
pregnant.
A girl.
They take away her.
Women of peasant aren't able to bear
children.
But he also wanted boy.
So he continued.
I hold knife at his throat and said:
"I don't bear German soldier."
"And next time I cut off your little wiener."
They fetch me and put me in waggon.
Long way. But if we reach Lodz we have chance.
Friends of mine living there.
Where are the others?
Dead.
All of them.
Pack it up. The attack will be ceased.
We retreating.
Water!
Your girlfriend?
My mother.
I write her, that I won't study at Heidegger this summer.
I can't die.
Good for you.
No, I mean,
my mother...
beared me when she was 48.
It's a wonder.
She raised me all by herself.
A simple women.
And the did go to the Wehrersatzkommando
and said,
that I am her only son and that I must study
and can't be conscripted.
Brave women.
She was detained for a whole night.
For delinquency.
A women, 68 years old.
Do you understand?
Lets go. Lets get out of here.
I'm sorry Martin. But I can't take you with me.
I bet.
- No way!
That was right in the heart.
Ah shit. That's Friedhelm.
Shit.
- I thought it was a Russian.
Why does he wear a...
- Just shut the fuck up!
Screams of agony
Do you hear me?
This one can wait.
Hit right aside of the left heart chamber.
Great loss of blood.
Not a chance.
Friedhelm? Friedhelm.
Friedhelm! Dr. Jahn!
What is with him?
Lost cause.
Put this one in OR.
That can't be.
I know him.
Please.
Put this one on the surgery table.
But hurry.
No, you don't! You don't.
Nurse Hildegard.
Don't die on me.
Friedhelm.
Wilhelm...
I write Wilhelm that you're alive.
No.
Wilhelm...
is dead.
"September 1943."
"At the beginning of the war
you fight for your fatherland."
"Later on, when you start having doubts,
you fight for your comrades,
that you don't want to forsake."
"But what happens if there isn't anyone left?"
"When you're alone."
"When you're the only one you can lie to is yourself."
"What are you fighting for, then?"
Take care of yourself.
I wish you from all my heart, that you will
find your luck. Yes.
Charlotte.
There you are.
Does it hurt badly?
- It's okay.
Oh God you're back.
Do you see, I was right!
I prayed that he will bring him back.
Yes.
Him.
Wilhelm will be come back.
I know it. I know that he is alive.
I have some flour and two eggs.
I can bake some cake.
I'm so sorry that
it was a centimeter off.
"Then we will track back home."
"Then we will be home again, home!"
"Then we will be back to home."
"Our flag it waves..."
- Gentlemen! Gentlemen!
Please welcome the wonderful,
unique Greta DelTorres.
A toast on the beauty of our german
women! - Cheers!
Well, already back? Well, I wasn't need
at the front anymore.
You should have made a small visit there.
Would you do us the honors and sing with us?
(Men) Aw girl, come one.
- Come.
Come here and sing with us.
Thanks, but I'm tired.
Come, girl.
Don't touch me!
Seems like she expected something better, huh?
We're not good enough for her.
Get a mouthful on the front fighters.
Only the mouth?
I have a surprise for you, gentlemen.
Seems like the final victory will be canceled.
Are you insane?
If you still want to be heroes
you better hurry.
What is her name?
Greta.
She tried to save me.
What she is do?
I would like to know that too.
We couldn't even say goodbye to each other.
Come out!
Get out!
We only stayed overnight.
We are already gone!
Go in there, now!
You can stay some days.
Thanks a lot.
Your friend doesn't speak a lot.
No.
I go to the market.
You two can help my son on the fields.
Till then.
You must disappear.
But... your father said...
He goes into the town.
People who help the partisans will be shot!
My father will betray to to the German.
What did he say?
He gets your people.
Follow me if you want to stay alive.
Come.
Russia 41, or? Did you participate?
- Sure. The wound stripe.
Infanterie-Sturmabzeichen.
The Mincemeat-Badge.
Nahkampfspange.
- Look, the Panzerkampfabzeichen.
How many did you crack open?
According to the newsreel they're
throwing their last reserves against us.
That's enough boys.
Leave the man alone. Get out!
Just because you are a hero
you won't to talk to us?
In one year i will be seventeen and
I will get more than you got.
This spoils us the war.
I am aware that the Obersturmbannführer is busy.
You keep telling me that for over a mont...
Did you tell him my na...
Rome is to close to the front line.
- But you promised!
Let your father eat in peace.
- Then Florence. I...
Please, dad! I want to see "The Birth of Venus" and
Michelangelo's "David".
Please!
- We talk another time.
Who was it?
Good luck!
Who are you?
I am Alina Bigaj, this is Viktor.
We are on the run from the Germans.
I don't understand.
But you said...
No, don't. No, no. No!
Mom... Mom, please.
- No!
Nothing will happen to me. Listen!
Nothing will happen to me.
No! No!
Hey, you over there! Come here.
We got lost.
Do you speak german?
Hey look.
Somebody here thinks that war is over for him.
Stand up.
Stand up!
Oberleutnant Winter. 3rd company,
60th infantery regiment.
Open up!
Get dressed.
What?
Now.
Please sit down.
Do I finally get...
Sit down!
I want an explanation...
This is a report of a Feldwebel which claims that
you expressed doubts on the final victory.
Did you make these statements?
Are you polish?
Yes.
Where are you from?
Warsaw.
I have a friend in Warsaw.
Junction Leszno / Ogrodowa. Franek Madajczyk.
Do you know him?
Polish
Everybody in Warsaw knows Franek Madajczyk!
That's maybe true.
But there is no Franek Madajczyk at the
junction Leszno / Ogrodowa.
Why not?
Because the Leszno and the Ogrodowa
never cross.
Is he german?
Why you be with a German?
Do you fuck him?
Are you jewish?
No.
Why are you so sure about that?
As you said: I fuck him.
He says something on polish.
There are snitches.
The Germans pay a bounty on your head.
Why should I keep you alive?
What a bugger! Why didn't you respond to
my cal...
Sit down.
What's the big idea?
Sit down!
Defeatism, demagoguery,
vilification of the Fuhrer.
You sent me there. Want me begone, away from Berlin,
away from you frigid wifey!
Shut it!
You can't arrest me.
You would arrest you own child as well.
I'm pregnant.
Door is unlocked.
I'm sorry. I tried my best in front
of the judge.
Amnesia after a grenade impact.
That we both served since '40 in france...
What's the verdict?
Revokation of all german civil rights
and...
death by firing squad,
execution tomorrow at six in the morning.
I...
can try to get a clemency app...
The war is already lost.
You just need to decide.
Die
or lie.
Wilhelm, I am...
It's okay.
"Most people think,
that war mainly consists of fighting."
"But that's not true."
"It's waiting:"
"for the next attack,
the next meal,
the next morning."