'Company...halt!'
Hitler! Hitler!
Munich. November 9th, 1923.
Opposed by government forces
Adolf Hitler's visionary ideas
of overthrowing
the Weimar Republic,
and establishing himself
as dictator ended abruptly
in his arrest
and conviction for treason.
During his imprisonment
in Landsberg fortress
Hitler laid down
the malevolent presets
which were
to guide Nazi Germany.
A ruthless blueprint
for political rape, genocide
and world conquest unequalled
in the history of mankind.
'Unremittingly, we shall poison
the relations'
'between the people
and states of all countries.'
By envy and hatred,
by struggle and warfare..
...and by spreading hunger,
destitution and plagues
we shall bring all people
to such a pass..
...that the only escape
will lie in total submission
to our domination.
Shall I read it back, my Fuhrer?
No.
But, some of the language
might be a bit too strong.
Abel, you still don't understand
the purpose of this book.
I have no desire to give comfort
to the church goers
the believers in democracy,
the crooked legged Jew vermin.
To the parasitic scum
who infest Germany
this will be a warning.
But a warning that
they will never accept.
No.
Mein Kampf is for those
who will follow me.
They will read it.
Believe it.
Act upon it.
'Mein Fuhrer!'
Now, I have been listening
to that drivel
for the last two days.
'You must think you are
Caesar, Napoleon and Bismarck'
huh, all rolled up in one.
They must've made a mistake
when they put you in here.
This is a prison.
Not a mental institution.
What is your name?
Oh, so you can have me shot
when you become
the lord of Germany.
It is Joseph Schonberg.
Lousy Jew!
There's not one drop
of Jewish blood in me.
But you don't have to be a Jew
to hold your nose
at the sewage pouring out
of this imitation messiah.
The German people still
believe in law and in order.
Here's a perfect example
of what I just told you.
The world will not
accept my warning.
Even when they hear it,
they won't believe it.
They will be shouting
the phrases about
decadent democracy as they are
led to the slaughter.
Released from Landsberg fortress
on December 20th, 1924.
Hitler immediately plunged
into the task of forging
the disbanded Nazi Party
into an instrument which
would enable him to achieve
his megalomaniac ambitions.
By 1928, tens of thousands,
mesmerized by his
hypnotic fanaticism,
had adopted Mein Kampf
as the Bible
of national socialism
and Hitler as their savior.
For his disciples,
Hitler selected those
who like himself, were among
the uprooted and disinherited.
Crippled in mind and body,
their lives could have meaning
in the unbalanced world
of totalitarianism.
Among them were Herman Goering,
a morphine addicted voluptuary
Ernst Rohm, a sadistic pervert
Heinrich Himmler, sinister,
inhuman executioner
Joseph Goebbels, club footed
vicious propagandist
Julius Streicher, whip
carrying, rabid anti-Semite
swearing absolute allegiance.
Each of them had dedicated
his life to Hitler
and the banner with
the black swastika.
Still fearing imprisonment
because of
the party's violent activities
Hitler provided himself with
the means of escape
by renting a modest villa,
overlooking the village
of Berchtesgaden, near the
border of his native Austria.
To act as housekeeper
and hostess
Hitler enlisted the services
of his half sister
Angelika Raubal.
Angelika.
I often hoped we would
see each other again.
And then your wonderful
telegram came.
You should have seen my friends
in Vienna when they found out
we were coming to live with you.
So, they were impressed, huh?
Impressed? All Austria
is talking about you.
'This is Friedl, your niece.'
Hello, uncle.
I didn't mention it
in my telegram.
But I really couldn't
leave them alone in Vienna.
Of course not. Them?
You have been fooling
with the travelling case
ever since we left Vienna.
Are you going to sit and laugh
like a silly goose all day?
Pick up your clothing.
I haven't said hello
to Uncle Adolph yet.
Hello, Uncle Adolph.
You know, my travelling cases
don't seem to hold
as much as they used to.
Even when they are
so carefully packed?
Adolph, you must not
encourage her.
She will take advantage of you.
'You mentioned
a house in your telegram.'
But I didn't expect
anything like this.
'Girls, look at it.'
It's just beautiful.
I think you had better
let Emil carry your bag.
Emil.
Oh, Uncle Adolph,
please show us the house.
- Heil Hitler!
Gentlemen..
Freidl and I were just doing
the spring cleaning.
Adolph didn't tell me
he was expecting you.
We didn't make an appointment.
However, it is necessary
that we speak with him.
But he isn't home.
He and Geli left early
this morning for a picnic.
Do you know where they might be?
They have several
favorite places.
If you gentlemen will make
yourselves comfortable
I will send Friedl
to look for them.
I still think we should have
telephoned the Fuhrer first.
No. This is too important.
Do you realize he only made
six speeches in the last year?
We are fighting
for our political life.
And you cannot win a campaign
by communing with nature
on a mountain top.
That depends on the campaign.
I hope you're not going
to put that one on the album.
Why not?
It's charming.
But overexposed.
For a moment, you reminded me
of someone.
A woman?
My mother.
When I was a boy, we used
to picnic alongside
a little stream.
Outside Linz.
She'd raise her skirt,
just as you did
'to keep it from getting wet.'
And I thought you were going
to reveal the details of some
secret love affair.
You better put on your shoes
and stockings.
You might catch a cold.
No, no, Uncle Alf.
This feels so good.
This mountain air makes me
so hungry.
I'll have to go on a diet
before I return to Vienna.
Why do you want
to go back to Vienna?
Well, I do miss the city.
But I thought you were
happy here with me.
Oh, I am, Uncle Alf.
It's just that I miss
the nightlife.
The theatres, the shops,
the dancing.
And Kort Linden.
You haven't mentioned him
for some time.
There's really nothing
much to say.
He's in Vienna and I'm here.
He's been writing
to you every week
at the Berchtesgaden
post office.
Emil was told when
one of your letters was given
to him by mistake.
And I practically did
everything but kiss that
fat-headed postmaster,
so he wouldn't say anything.
Mama would have
a fit if she knew.
What about this Kort?
But you know,
I'm not seeing him.
Geli, you're avoiding
my question.
That sounds just like mama.
Has she been talking
to you about Kort?
Mothers can be
a problem sometimes.
Geli, I am you uncle.
I'm responsible for you.
Surely, you have nothing
to hide from me
between you and Kort.
But that's something personal.
If you won't tell me then
I should have to insist
that he stop writing to you.
I don't think that Kort would
give me up that easily.
Then, I will have to see
that he does.
Uncle Alf, you're jealous.
My mother, always my mother.
'Uncle Adolph. Geli.'
'Uncle Adolph! Geli!'
Oh, Uncle Adolph, they are-
Is Uncle Adolf angry?
Friedl..
...do you remember the picture
of Uncle Adolf's mother?
- The one mama showed us?
- Yes.
Is she wearing anything
around her neck?
A pendant or a necklace?
No, not a necklace.
It's a cameo and a gold chain.
'Geli, what is it?'
Nothing, help me
with the things.
The Fuhrer is coming.
Heil Hitler.
Well, I thought I had made
my position quiet clear
about visitors.
I did not come here to
exchange social amenities.
Your presence is needed in
Munich for the coming election.
As lead of the party
in the north, I insist.
- Insist?
- The party will demand it.
Listen to this
and don't you ever forget it.
I am the party!
'Mein Fuhrer.'
We have all worked too hard
and sacrificed too much
to let the movement
disintegrate.
What I am doing here is more
important to the future
of the party than any political
activity I might undertake.
The second volume of Mein Kampf
will be the corner stone
of a new Germany
which will last
for a thousand years!
But my, Fuhrer, surely you could
continue with this
most important work in Munich.
No.
I shall remain here
until it is completed.
- 'But my Fuhrer--'
- 'My decision is final.'
Gentlemen,
my mother has prepared
something to eat
in the dining room.
'Geli..'
Geli, you must not be angry.
I am not angry.
I just don't understand.
Geli, I..
I have no explanation.
Give me the cameo.
I will take it to Munich
and have it repaired.
No, we will go to Munich
together and shop for a new one.
- When? Today?
- Right after lunch.
I will hurry and get ready.
Oh, Geli. Help Friedl serve.
I can't. I have to pack.
'I go to Munich
with Uncle Adolf.'
Eat gentlemen.
We must leave immediately
for Munich.
- Sieg.
- Heil.
Perhaps we should ask
the Fuhrer's permission.
Oh, he won't mind.
They make a handsome couple,
don't they?
I doubt that the Fuhrer would
express his appreciation.
Who is the young man
she is dancing with?
No idea.
But I may as well find out.
I am sure the Fuhrer
will be interested.
If my figures are correct
we are now the second largest
party in Germany.
6.5 million votes,
107 seats in the Reichstag.
Strasser..
Reichstag is not
an end in itself
but merely the means to an end.
We win seats in order that we
may do away with the Reichstag.
That we have won today is merely
another weapon in our battle.
Call it whatever you will.
I believe we won
a great victory.
We should save the word victory,
until we achieve our goal.
Until then we should use
the word fight.
Next election will not be a race
for seats in the Reichstag
but my campaign for the
presidency against Hindenburg.
Lieutenant Erich Faber,
of Gerling staff.
Adolf, sit down.
This is disgraceful.
Strasser, if you have any
misgivings about my conduct
I suggest that you
keep them to yourself.
Not if you insist on submitting
the party to ridicule.
'The party has nothing
whatsoever'
'to do with my personal life.'
Fuhrer, you can disassociate
one from the other.
Your relationship with Geli
is a subject of common
gossip through Munich.
How dare you!
Our relationship has been
solely that of uncle to niece.
Then you have compromised
her, needlessly.
Maintaining her alone in your
apartment for the last year.
We may occupy the same apartment
but we do not share
the same bedroom.
If that's true, then I suggest
you either marry her
or send her back to her mother.
Strasser, you have gone too far,
there is no room for
a petty bourgeois moralist in
the National Social Party.
I shall not tolerate
any further discussion
about my relationship with Geli.
I am afraid you will
still hear about it.
Whether you like it or not.
Not even you can order
an ugly rumor like this
to stop from circulating.
That will be all, lieutenant.
Heil Hitler.
Get your wrap.
But the evening has just begun.
I'd like to stay and dance.
The lieutenant will be occupied
with other duties.
'Achtung!'
- 'Heil Hitler.'
- Heil Hitler.
What an evening.
I wish you would win
elections more often.
And if you just wouldn't
get so angry about things.
How long have you known him?
'Lieutenant Faber, the man
with whom you danced tonight.'
Oh, is that his name?
I forgot to ask.
I just happened to think
of his face
when he brought me back
to the table.
You frightened that poor boy
out of his wits.
Well, he should have
asked for my permission.
He didn't even ask for mine.
I practically kidnapped him.
He didn't know
what was happening
until he found himself
dancing with me.
Anyway, I didn't think
you'd notice me.
you were so busy with
Herr Strasser.
Strasser..
...is determined to be
the conscience of the party.
Do you know that
he actually accused us
of living immorally?
Did you tell him
the intimate details?
No, Geli.
Well..
Strasser needn't worry
about you seducing me.
I can't even get you to
help me with my buttons.
Please, Uncle.
The top one is difficult.
I wonder what made him bring up
the subject in the first place.
Strange...you have
never even kissed me.
Haven't you opened it yet?
It is open..
...Geli.
- 'You despise me.'
- No, I don't.
- 'I can see it in your eyes.'
- You are wrong.
Don't lie to me.
Perhaps, it would be better
for both of us
if I return to Vienna.
No, you will remain here.
But you know there can
never be anything between us.
Please, let me go
back to Vienna.
I can start
my music lessons again.
Is that all?
And what about Kort Linden?
We haven't written to
each other since I came
to Munich a year ago.
I am sure you haven't
forgotten each other.
Picking up that cheap affair
where you left off
will be no problem.
Whatever there was between Kort
and myself was not cheap.
You filthy slut!
What-what about those weekends
you spent with him in Linz?
They were wonderful.
Kort made me feel like a woman.
Something you would never
be capable of doing.
Why, you never loved me.
You never loved any woman.
You couldn't. Your mother.
- Always your mother.
- Damn your vile mouth!
You can't live with the
knowledge of your shame.
So you have tried to bury
it in distractive hatred.
Hatred for the world, for life,
for yourself!
Sieg heil!
The Fuhrer has struck
a blow for freedom.
But you'll never
be free. Never!
You'll see her image
in every woman's face
'just as you
saw it in mine tonight.'
No. No, no!
These things were never
meant to cloth me.
You were dressing
the nightmare in your mind.
Look at me.
I dare you to look at me
and tell me who you see.
'And Strasser is worried
about our relationship.'
I wonder how he'd really
feel if he knew
the mighty Fuhrer
was less than a man.
Good morning, Emil, Himmler.
Please, won't you come in?
Good morning Geli,
you look pale.
I didn't sleep well.
Unc..
The Fuhrer isn't here.
He left early this morning.
I-I was just packing.
I'm going home, to Vienna.
'If you want to wait,
make yourselves comfortable.'
You'll excuse me, while I pack.
There is some wine in the..
No, Emil.
Don't..
Please, let me telephone
Uncle Adolf.
Let me talk to him.
Suicide?
Did she leave a note?
Yes. Yes, I'll inform
the Furher.
My Fuhrer, I have bad news.
- What is it?
- Geli is dead.
'Himmler and Maurice
just found her body.'
'The gun is
still in her hand.'
No. No.
No, it-it can't be true.
Not my Geli.
Why did she do this to me?
Geli. Oh, my Geli.
I'm sorry.
Strasser, perhaps you had better
take care of
the necessary arrangements.
I think you had better leave.
I'll stay here with the Fuhrer.
Heinrich, Strasser should be
there in a few minutes.
Be careful.
The Fuhrer? The Fuhrer's
grief is overwhelming.
But I'm sure he will recover.
You almost had Strasser
in tears.
And for a minute I thought you
were going to use that gun.
What do you mean? If Strasser
hadn't stop me, I would have.
She's the only woman
I have ever loved.
Her death is the greatest
loss I shall ever suffer.
But then, why did you order
Himmler and Maurice to kill her?
You wouldn't understand.
No one would.
But Geli knew.
It was either her life or mine.
Anna, the patients gone?
Yes, doctor.
But they looked quite upset.
Why can't he make appointments
like any normal person?
Because my dear Anna,
our patient
is not exactly a normal person.
Oedipus complex,
megalomania, impotency.
Any one of these psychic
disturbances could comprise
a case history in itself.
Anna, see if
the side door is open.
Yes, doctor.
Is anyone else in the office,
beside the doctor?
No.
And you stay out
of the doctor's office.
My Fuhrer.
Heil Hitler.
Well, how does
your patient look?
Frankly, quite exhausted.
I imagine your last campaign for
the presidency
must have been strenuous.
Running against
Hindenburg wasn't easy.
That swine Strasser..
...resigned just when
I needed him most.
But you did get over
13 million votes
and 230 seats of Reichstag.
That should at least ensure
your appointment as chancellor.
No, it's only a matter of days.
But I did not come here
to discuss politics.
You know what is bothering me
those damn nightmares!
- I can't sleep.
- Yes, I know.
- What are you writing?
- 'Merely the date.'
January 20th, 1933.
It's been quite sometime
since I've last seen you.
The future chancellor of Germany
reduced to a case history.
It is quite confidential.
I assure you.
And quite useless.
What do I think of my parents,
my brother, my sister's room?
Du scheinst.
What has all this got
to do with my nightmares?
As I have indicated in the past,
the patient's background
is often the only clue
to his traumatic disturbances.
But this has been going on
for almost two years.
You have dragged things from me
that no other
living being has ever known.
Would you like to
remove your hat and coat?
No.
Now, you began to
suffer from these nightmares
shortly after the tragic
loss of your niece.
That has nothing to do with it.
Take this.
What good are they?
If these nightmares don't stop,
it will be the end of me.
The end of everything.
I'm afraid there's
little I can do
unless you are
willing to cooperate.
How much longer am I expected to
continue with
this-this nonsense?
The length of the treatment,
usually depends upon
the patient's willingness
to face the facts.
- 'In your case, Geli--'
- I told you.
That has nothing whatsoever
to do with my nightmares.
You must let me be
the judge of what is pertinent.
As your physician--
And there will be
no more confessions.
I refuse to tolerate your
morbid curiosity any longer.
And you had better destroy that.
My secretary will contact you.
Be prepared to come to Berlin.
Finally, we have arrived.
Chancellor of Germany.
- Now, we begin.
- Yeah!
London, Paris, Washington.
International Jewish conspiracy.
This criticism is intolerable.
But mein Fuhrer,
it is impossible
to restrict the activities
of the foreign press.
But you can prevent this poison
from being distributed
in Germany.
The opposition
press within Germany
is publishing the same story.
Then they must be silenced!
We may not be able to suppress
word and opinion but I shall not
tolerate any criticism
of our policies at home.
- There have been arrests.
- And acquittals.
My liberal judges
and democratic courts
they too must be eliminated.
I can't move in any direction.
President Hindenburg above me,
Vice Chancellor Von Papen below.
Only three seats
in a cabinet of ten.
When a cabinet doesn't restrict
me, the Reichstag does.
I am encircled and entrapped!
This opposition must
end once and for all!
'Simple.'
Just give me three days
and a free hand
with my brown-shirts.
You shall have it.
The time has come
for heads to roll.
Wherever we find them.
In the courts,
the press, the Reichstag
the trade unions,
the churches--
Mein Fuhrer, but people are
religiously inclined.
Perhaps we should refrain
from activities
against the church,
at this time.
One is either a German or
a Christian, you can't be both.
The symbol of our religion is
not the cross, but the swastika.
As for worship,
let the people look to me.
I am their father.
Mein Fuhrer, your position
as our true
spiritual leader
is unquestionable.
But don't you think
it may be a bit premature
to incur the antagonism
of religious groups?
Antagonism?
Ernst, there will
be no exceptions.
And the justifications
for these corrective measures?
The action which you have
held in reserve
for just such an occasion.
Arrangements have been
complete for some time.
The only question will be when?
Tonight.
Mein Fuhrer,
under the circumstances
perhaps we should
cancel our dinner party.
Not at all.
It will be ideal
to have the press
for after dinner cocktails.
The view from your window
should be excellent.
- Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler.
The clerk from the
photographer is here.
with certain pictures
for Herr Goebbels
Have her come in.
The pictures of
the inauguration ceremony.
I need one
for a special release.
- Heil Hitler.
- Bring them over here.
All of these feature Hindenburg.
- I'll have them retouched.
- Hmm.
'I suppose you have seen
these pictures.'
Fraulein.
Which do you prefer?
This one.
Why?
Well, it's-it's masculine.
I think it will appeal to women.
At least, it does to me.
I think she is right.
Use this one.
Ah there are some corrections
to be made. I'll call later.
Heil Hitler.
Mein Fuhrer, your car is ready.
Uh, by the way, what was
that young lady's name?
Uh, Braun.
Eva Braun.
Arrange for her to be my guest
at the dinner party tonight.
'Would you believe that some
gentleman of the foreign press'
'are reporting only
what you see on the surface.'
The deep inner rot
infecting Germany today
can only be destroyed by the use
of the most stringent
discipline.
Discipline? What I have
personally witnessed could
only be described as
the most shocking brutality.
'Let me make it clear.'
'For us, there can be but one
decision! We shall fight.'
Until the last vestiges of this
bourgeois republic are erased.
And a new Germany
reborn in the spirit
of national socialism
is once more master
of its own destiny.
Mein Fuhrer.
That was inspiring.
All of Germany
should have heard you.
Is there anything wrong?
Do you usually wear
your hair that way?
No I...put it up
especially for this evening.
I prefer your hair the way
you wore it this afternoon.
Oh, I'm sorry if I had
only known that--
You can use Frau Goebbels'
dressing room.
It's through that door.
Do you want me
to change it...now?
I have already stated
my preference.
You'd think he had nothing
in his mind but that girl.
I hope the press has
the same impression.
Won't Frau and Harry Guderian
be here this evening?
No...business.
Little party matter
which requires
Herr Guderian's attention.
What possible attraction
could she have for him?
Doesn't she remind you
of someone?
- Geli.
- Of course.
Well, now that is better.
Much better.
You should always wear
your hair this way.
Yes?
The Reichstag.
Yes-yes, I'll inform the Fuhrer.
Mein Fuhrer, the Reichstag
has been set on fire.
Arson.
Open those drapes.
This is monstrous!
This is the work of
an incendiary conspiracy.
Liberals, social democrats.
The Catholic Center Party, Jews.
Jews, Jews!
The iron fist of
national socialism
shall descend on all of them.
The flames rising from
the Reichstag shall become
a torch of retribution.
I can promise you that this fire
which our enemies have ignited
'shall be extinguished
with their blood!'
Terror will be broken by terror.
No!
Confine the Dachau.
Radissons 857.
Social Democrats, 912.
Catholic Center Party, 3569.
Jews, 4296.
From all over Germany.
Adolf, I put the storm troopers
together for you.
But I'll be damned if
I let you sell them out.
I-If you believe that
you must be insane.
Where did you get that idea
from? Your friend Heinz?
From a confidential report
of that meeting you held
with the general staff.
Read it.
Report of General Von Brauwich.
"The General Staff considers
Anstreben and the S.A. hostile
"in every respect
to it's intimus.
"Their restraint would be
a primary consideration
in any agreement to support you
as Hindenburg's successor."
And this is your answer.
"Gentlemen, if we are of
one accord, I can give you
"my personal assurance that
you may regard the demands
by Captain Rohm and the S.A.
as utterly inconsequential."
Have you forgotten your promise
that the S.A. would
take over army leadership?
Our very existence is threatened
and all you're concerned about
is the army leadership.
Threatened? By what?
My S.A. has swept
the streets clean.
Since the Reichstag fire
all political opposition
has been completely eliminated.
Those who haven't fled
the country are either dead
or in concentration camps.
Because a few thousand swine
are either dead or in prison.
You think we can do what
we want when we can't.
'Hindenburg still occupies
the presidential palace.'
Hindenburg, that old man
is practically dead.
Exactly.
But apparently, you fail
to realize that his death
means the end
of national socialism.
The end of everything.
Here's a copy of the last
will of testament
of our beloved president.
'It will be published
upon his death.'
It asks the general staff to
restore the monarchy to power.
Those pigs could never fulfill
that request.
The S.A. put the Nazi party in
power and will keep it there.
No.
Civil war with the army
is not the answer.
Negotiations with
the general staff
are our only means
to a bloodless solution.
The only solution acceptable
to the general staff would be
the liquidation of the S.A.
Ernst, have you forgotten
what I said to you
at the Nuremberg rally?
You and the S.A.
are my right arm.
Then use it or the general staff
will chop it off.
Ernst, you are my best friend.
Trust me.
Whatever arrangements I may
have to make will only be
because they are expedient.
Even if I should be wrong, I
know I can always rely upon you
and the S.A. to rectify
my mistake.
Believe me, if there's
any mistake, the general staff
would have made it.
'I knew I could depend
upon my Ernst.'
Yeah, this is going
to be difficult to explain.
Next month, every ranking
S.A. officer will be meeting
at the annual conclave.
They're expecting
my announcement
that they've been given command
of the regular army.
It is only a matter of time.
Suppose I should attend
the conclave
and address them personally.
- Would you?
- Of course.
Adolf, that will be
a night to remember.
- Putzi, am I glad to see you?
- Glad to see you too.
- Let's go upstairs.
- Good.
Edmond, Edmond Heines.
There's a package here
for Captain Rohm.
- I'll give it him.
- Thank you.
- Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler
Come in.
Oh, Edmond.
This package came for you.
Good.
Hmm, whatever you're using
is really nice.
Oh, thank you.
Comes from Paris.
I'll get some for you.
How goes it downstairs?
It's a biggest turnout
we ever had.
Good. The Fuhrer
will be pleased.
- You really think he'll come?
- You read his telegram.
Oh, and I've really got
a big surprise for him.
Open it.
'Well, what do you think of it"
"Mein Fuhrer to our
everlasting friendship, Ernst."
I didn't know you're so
sentimental about friendship.
Oh, Edmond.
Don't be stupid.
This visit calls for some
token of appreciation.
I still don't understand
your reason
for this sudden admiration.
If anyone deserves
a plaque, it should be you.
Guderian is a full general.
That little club foot
Goebbels is a cabinet minister.
Himmler is in charge
of the S.S. and the Gestapo.
What has he ever given you?
Friendship.
'Now you should be in charge
of Germany's military forces.'
Edmond, it's just
a matter of time.
You heard him.
He promised me.
The Fuhrer gets nervous when
he's reminded of his promises.
I think it's only because
he's a little frightened.
I put him at the head of
three million storm troopers
and suddenly he isn't quite sure
whether they're marching
behind him or coming after him.
Come now, let us go down.
I want to talk to the chef
about the Fuhrer's dinner.
Heil Hitler, the vegetarian.
Oh, Edmond, really come.
Shoot that dog.
Adolf, what is the meaning?
What are you doing?
Stop him.
Adolf.
- Stop them.
- Traitor.
Now you'll see how
I'll deal with those
who conspire against me.
And Heines shall be the first.
Stop them before it's too late.
There's no conspiracy,
there never has been.
- Liar.
- Wha..
You and your circle
of corruption were planning
to assassinate me
and seize the state.
That's not true and you know it.
- Now, countermand that order.
- No.
Before this day is over
I shall have cleaned
out this filthy pig sty.
Not only here,
but throughout Germany.
I have no place
for scum like you
and Heines
in my new world order.
You sick, ominous hypocrite.
When did you acquire
this sudden morality?
'After your negotiations
with the generals staff?'
'Ernst!'
Ernst!
Is that the price you agreed
to pay the general staff?
'You bought their support
with our lives.'
But there's another reason
why I must die, isn't it, Adolf?
One that goes back to
your barracks in 1919.
Do you remember that filthy
pig sty, Adolf, best friend?
You can't permit me to live
because I'm the proof
of your own corruption.
Get him out of here!
- You..
- Get rid of him!
'Get rid of him!
Get rid of him!'
'Company..'
'Halt.'
'In the name of the Fuhrer.'
'Heil Hitler.'
'Fire.'
Open up.
Troupe leader, William Smith.
Stand up, ferul.
No, I don't wanna die.
No.
- No.
- Let me go along with him.
No.
- No.
- Take him away.
'No.'
I don't wanna die.
No. No.
No.
Don't. No, I don't wanna die.
The Fuhrer has granted you
this courtesy.
Use it.
If Hitler wants to see me dead
he will have to
shoot me himself.
'In the name of the Fuhrer.'
'Heil Hitler.'
'Fire.'
In the name of the Fuhrer.
Hands up.
Fire.
'In the name of Fuhrer.'
Heil Hitler.
Fire.
Save it for the Fuhrer.
Tell him, I returned
the courtesy.
In the name of the Fuhrer.
Heil Hitler.
Fire.
Mutinies must be suppressed with
the iron law of decimation.
The group, headed by
Chief of staff, Ernst Rohm
And Strasser, were the criminals
of this conspiracy against
the security of our Government.
I myself ask
to be taken into custody.
I gave the order to shoot
those who were the ringleaders
of this conspiracy.
I further gave the order
to burn down the raw flesh
the ulcers poisoning the
well springs of Germany.
If anyone reproaches me
and asked me why
I did not resort to the regular
courts of justice for conviction
of these offenders, then all
I've to say to them is this..
...in that hour..
...I was responsible
for the fate of Germany
and thereby I became
the supreme judge
of the German people.
Eva.
Mm-hmm?
Where are you going?
It's a personal invitation
from the Fuhrer.
To the Berghof.
Oh, Gretl.
I'm going to be with him
for a whole week.
But what about your job?
Do you think anyone would
dare to dismiss me
while I'm the Fuhrer's guest?
Who cares anyway?
Gretl.
Be a good sister and let me
borrow your negligee?
Aren't you being
a bit too hopeful?
You've been in love
with him for eight months
and he hasn't shown
the slightest interest in you.
That way.
Oh, he hasn't been
that indifferent.
But you can't expect
the most important man
in Germany to fall
in love, just like that.
What has love
have to do with it?
You're not the first woman
who's had an invitation
to the Berghof.
But I'm goin' to be the last.
You let me know the minute
he's pronounced dead.
What is it, Bormann?
Fraulein Braun has arrived.
This line will be
kept open for you.
Hindenburg won't last this day.
- And the will?
- Von Papen's orders.
It will be never be published.
Nothing can stop me now.
By this time tomorrow,
I shall be master of Germany.
And then mankind will know,
with whom it has to deal.
My Fuhrer.
May I please have my robe?
'It's lying on the foot
of the bed.'
'This concludes
our broadcasting for today.'
'There has been
no further bulletin'
"from physicians attending the
Great President Von Hindenburg"
'Reich Chancellor Hitler
is still conferring'
'with his cabinet
at the Berghof.'
That's not true.
Reich Chancellor Hitler
is conferring with Eva Braun.
Eva Bruan.
'But Reich's Chancellor Hitler
should be with his cabinets.'
I'm sure they can wait.
At least, until I comb my hair.
Perhaps...even a little longer.
I'm so happy you invited me.
The week will seem like a day.
Well, then we-we shall have to
extend the invitation.
Aren't you going
to arrange your hair?
I'll have to wait..
...until it's dry.
My Fuhrer.
Is there anything wrong?
What do you mean?
- Was my kiss so distasteful?
- I don't want to discuss it.
There's something about me
that is frightening you.
I've nothing to fear.
You understand? Nothing!
You are Eva Braun.
A photographer's clerk.
A street-walker.
A filthy tramp with whom
I can do anything I wish.
- My Fuhrer!
- You are Eva Braun.
Say it.
- I am Eva Braun.
- Again.
I am Eva Braun.
Look at me!
No.
You could never
be anything...but her.
My Fuhrer.
Berlin just called.
President Hindenburg died
five minutes ago.
- Has Himmler left for Berlin?
- Not yet.
He and the others are waiting
for any last instructions
you may have.
Martin, order my car.
You will see that Fraulein Braun
is driven home immediately.
Yes, my Fuhrer.
'Fraulein Braun.'
'The car will be waiting for you
in half an hour.'
'Please be ready.'
What did you hope to accomplish
with these cheap melodramatics?
Did you think that will change
anything between us?
When you have...wanted something
more than life itself
and you discover
you can never possess it
'what else was there
for me to do?'
But you must have been aware
that my interest in you
was not based on love.
Perhaps not love.
I would have settled for less.
But what did you hope to gain
from any relationship with me?
Prestige? Influence? Money?
I looked for no reward
other than to serve my Fuhrer.
It is impossible
for me to accept that.
Because of her?
The woman you see
when you look at me?
Where does she end?
Where do I begin?
You mustn't.
Why can't you leave me in peace?
'Please.'
I can't stand it any longer.
'Adolf.'
Why must you torture me
like this?
I am your son.
I'll never be anything but her.
It doesn't matter.
Believe me.
It just doesn't matter.
I understand.
Do you?
Can you understand
this compulsion
which fills me with disgust?
That turns me away
from every woman.
I am not like other men.
Desire turns to revulsion.
Gratification,
which even an animal enjoys
is denied me.
Can you understand that?
Yes...and even more than that.
But it doesn't have
to be that way any longer.
It is useless.
There can be no happiness for me
as long as she exists.
But she is dead.
No matter how real
she may seem to you
'she has only existed
in your mind.'
'Adolf, look at me.'
'The proof that she
is no longer there'
'is in your eyes.'
The death
of President Von Hindenburg
on August 2nd, 1934
removed the last obstacle
to complete power for Hitler.
Virtually unchallenged,
Hitler consolidated the offices
of president and chancellor
establishing
an absolute dictatorship.
It was the beginning
of Hitler's New World Order.
A barbaric concept designed
for enslaving humanity.
In a continual display of power
designed to intimidate
and impress the world
Hitler's massive legions
marched triumphantly
under the banner
of the twisted cross.
Adhering faithfully
to his precept
of total obedience.
They swore unconditionally
to lay down their lives
for their Fuhrer.
To implement Hitler's dream
of world conquest
factories
were secretly converted
from civilian
to military production.
Rearmament became Germany's
most important industry.
On March 7th, 1936, convinced
of his infallible destiny
to rule the world
Hitler set in motion
the destructive forces
which were, ultimately,
to cost the lives
of 50 million people.
Gentlemen,
at this historic moment
three battalions
of German troops
are marching..
...in the Marine land.
By this action
I have not only broken
the shackles
of the Versailles Treaty
but I have also opened the door
to our future victories.
The conquest and subjugation
of Europe will be our next task.
After that...the world!
'Nexus in Austria
wipes out forever
'the artificial barriers'
'between the
German-speaking nations.'
'As of this day,
we are one people'
'one culture, under one law.'
Now that the question
of the Sudetenland
has been peacefully resolved
I welcome Czechoslovakia
into the German sphere.
'Germany's desire for peace
has been constantly threatened'
'by Poland's armed might.'
'This intolerable danger
to the German nation'
'must be ruthlessly crushed.'
There will be
a final reckoning with France
the inexorable mortal enemy
of the German people.
She will never be permitted
to rise again as a nation.
'Violence shall serve
as an example'
'to the smaller nations,
that resistance is futile.'
'As for our violation
of neutrality and subjugation'
'of non-combatant countries'
'who will there be left
to protest'
'after we have
conquered Europe?'
Slavic peoples
are to be regarded as sub-human
fit only for enslavement
or extermination.
Except for ineffectual
pockets of resistance
in Moscow and Stalingrad,
Europe is ours.
And even as Hitler
gloated in triumph
these pockets of resistance
exploded in violent
counter attacks
Coordinated
with massive allied action
throughout the world
on a scale unprecedented
in modern warfare.
The Nazi juggernaut
began to crumble.
Surrender?
"Unable to resist
Russian offensive any longer."
"Von Paulus."
I will not be denied
total victory.
Von Paulus
should have died fighting.
Set an example to his troops.
And I made him a Field Marshal.
My Fuhrer.
As we advised you
prior to that operation
Von Paulus might have
defeated the Russians.
But no one has ever won a
victory over the Russian snow.
Marshal Rommel,
snow may have been reason
for Von Paulus defeat.
What was yours?
If my memory serves me right,
snow is as rare as your victory
- in North Africa.
- The loss of North Africa--
Reasons. Excuses. Explanations.
They apply only to defeat.
No one has to explain victory.
It speaks for itself.
Let me make myself clear,
gentlemen.
These reverses must stop.
My Fuhrer.
It is our considered opinion
that an armistice now
may permit us to retain
what we already hold.
And prevent
the ultimate obliteration
of Germany.
Am I to understand
that you are already preparing
an excuse for defeat?
As of this day, further excuses
will not be accepted.
Any officer
who finds it necessary
to offer one
will answer to me, personally..
...with his life.
Heil Hitler!
Members of the general staff
will meet Fuhrer in my office.
All others are to return
to their posts.
Gentlemen.
In the interest of the state..
...it is my opinion that the
time has come for us to act.
I shall deliver my report
to the Fuhrer
at the first opportunity.
Colonel Stauffenberg.
There can be no margin
for error.
Our lives
and the fate of Germany
will depend on it.
We are ready for you now,
my Fuhrer.
Heil Hitler.
I will be ready for your report
in a few minutes.
We believe
the most effective method
of implementing your plan
without weakening
our western defenses
would be to use the Hungarian
and Romanian troops.
'I'm afraid they don't have
much stomach for fighting..'
'...and their loyalty
is questionable at best.'
A breakthrough would mean
the loss of Poland.
Whose briefcase is this?
Uh, it belongs to me, my Fuhrer.
Well, get it out of my way.
You had better check
Oberst Stauffenberg's report.
This is going to require
all of my attention.
Let me have your report, Oberst.
Here.
I'm sorry, General.
This is the wrong briefcase.
I have the report
in my other bag in the car.
I shall be back in a minute.
- Where's Brandt?
- Oberst Brandt.
What is the disposition
of our troops in this area?
My Fuhrer!
Call Himmler!
Not until the last one
of these dogs is destroyed!
Drop 'em!
- Heil Hitler!
- General Guderian?
- Yes.
The Fuhrer's expecting us.
'You will remove your side arms,
and open your bags.'
These bags contain
secret maps and documents.
We're not interested in
your maps and documents.
Open those bags!
I will not submit
to this indignity.
Those are the Fuhrer's orders!
For everyone!
- Heil Hitler!
Good morning, General Guderian.
- Fraulein Braun.
- Gentlemen.
Gentlemen, the Fuhrer.
'Heil Hitler!'
You may as well stay here.
My distinguished staff, you're
refrained from using the word
"retreat", in front of a woman.
- My Fuhrer--
- But, isn't it true?
Every time, I talk to one
of you, I only hear
of some new disaster.
I warn you...I will not tolerate
any further requests
for withdrawal of troops.
My Fuhrer, I'm afraid
it's too late for withdrawal.
East Prussia has been
cut-off from the right.
The enemy crossed
the Oder river last night.
What is the present position?
100 miles from Berlin.
You! Y-you you are responsible!
You should have prevented
that crossing
no matter what the cost!
I pulled back at the last moment
to avoid complete annihilation.
I-I-I'm not interested
in saving lives.
Your orders were to defend
the position to the last man!
My Fuhrer, I'm willing
to die for Germany.
But I refuse to die
without purpose.
You swore an oath
to me, to risk your life
at my command!
It is my decision,
mine alone, whether
your life has any purpose!
General Keitl, you will issue
a directive in my name
to all the armed forces.
Any soldier, or officer
who fails to defend his position
or retreats one step
'is to be summarily shot!'
Martin, get my things ready.
I'm leaving for Berlin.
Headquarters will be established
at the Fuhrerbunker.
You'll report to me there.
My Fuhrer, we have neither
the arms, nor the men
to continue this war.
I suggest we seek an armistice.
Swine!
Do you wish to add high treason
to an act of cowardice?
I shall never capitulate!
Nothing will change
my decision to fight
until I have achieved victory!
Now, get out, all of you!
Adolf..
...let me
go with you.
No, it'd be too dangerous.
But you'd need
someone to take care of you.
Bormann will be with me.
Please.
I'll meet you at the car.
Eva.
This is the greatest
challenge I've ever faced.
I must be free to cope with it.
I will have no time for you.
Victory. All that matters is
victory. I'm going with you.
You will remain here
at the Berghof.
I forbid you to come to Berlin.
How many times must
I tell you that there can be
no personal life for us.
Marriage or otherwise
until this war is won.
Adolf...if we should
lose the war, what then?
Even you.
Adolf, General Guderian
indicated there's no hope
and the others agreed with him.
General Guderian is
a fool. They're all fools.
Despite everything, I shall
not be deprived of victory.
'Our beloved Fuhrer
has sworn to remain here'
'and defend the
reign that has arrived.'
'In this, our greatest ordeal'
'we must prove that we are
worthy of his leadership.'
'Our Fuhrer expects no less.'
The enemy must pay with blood.
For every foot of German soil,
he occupies.
General Keitel. Urgent.
Well.
My Fuhrer, Germany
has been cut in two.
The Americans have
crossed the Elbe river
at a point only
sixty miles from Berlin.
The only forces we have intact
are north of this line.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Order them to counter-attack.
Must I do everything?
My Fuhrer, with the armament
plants in Upper Silesia
and the river
now held by the enemy
'we are no longer able
to procure supplies.'
The failure to destroy those
plants was an act of treason.
Nothing's to be left
intact for the allies.
I want the country laid waste.
We shall leave them nothing
but the scorched earth.
My Fuhrer,
I beg you to reconsider.
Those resources must be
spared for the German people.
The welfare of the
weaklings who survive
this war is of no concern to me.
They are not fit
to be called Germans.
If we should lose
this war, I will take
what is left of Germany with me.
- Where's the Fuhrer?
- He's not in his bedroom.
Let's try the conference room.
I will be with you
gentlemen in a minute.
Fuhrer, the enemy has penetrated
the outskirts of Berlin.
Their guns zeroed
in on the bunker.
I have just completed
the details of a plan
which will change
the entire course of war.
'The allies believe
that we have lost the war.'
That we will remain un-defensive
until we're destroyed.
But we will not play
their game. Ha-ha-ha.
'We shall take offensive.'
With the focus of Berlin center,
General Vince's army will attack
in the South
and General Steiner's army
will flank the
enemy on the North.
Well?
My Fuhrer, the
armies of General Vince
and General Steiner
no longer exist.
We should keep
General Heinrich's ninth army
in reserve.
That should take care
of any unforeseen contingencies.
Mein Fuhrer,
Heinrich's army surrendered
to the American
forces, last week.
No such thing has occurred.
I'm well aware of your
desires to end this war.
Make no mistake, gentlemen.
There should be
no attempts of armistice
as long as I am in command.
This counter-offensive will
go forward as scheduled.
I shall expect
your hourly reports.
Eva..
...I didn't think
you could get through.
What's wrong with the Fuhrer?
He's been this
way since yesterday.
We are unable to make him
understand, the war is lost.
He ordered a counter-offensive
by armies that
simply do not exist.
Berlin?
My Fuhrer, no one seems to know
anything about a counterattack.
Josef, Martin. Where are
the General Keitel
and General Yodl?
They all attempted
to leave yesterday
supervise a counter-attack.
Why haven't I heard from them?
I shall not tolerate
this gross insubordination.
Adolf...there is no counter
offensive.
There never will be.
I have been betrayed
by everyone. Resented by all.
I have been surrounded
by conspirators.
Murderers. Cowards. Traitors.
Himmler, Goering, the general
staff, the army.
Even those filthy swine.
The German people
have failed me.
I hold them all
responsible for our defeat.
The enemy did not win this war.
Victory was given to them.
And I could have made myself,
master of the world.
Adolf.
You should have
remained at the Berghof.
The radio announced
your decision to remain
here until the end.
My place is with you.
Do you realize
what that end will be?
I've come to share it
with you. As your wife.
Do you, Adolf Hitler, swear
that you are of Aryan descent
'and free of any
hereditary disease?'
I do.
'Do you, Eva Braun,
swear that you're'
'of Aryan descent and free
of any hereditary disease?'
I do.
Then, in the presence
of these witnesses
and under the laws
of the Third Reich..
...as of this day April 29,
1945, you are man and wife.
Heil Hitler.
Adolf...let me be first.
I don't want to see you die.
The gun is quicker.
It won't make any difference.
We are to be cremated.
I won't have them making
a spectacle of our bodies.
No. No, of course not.
But it doesn't matter.
I shall be proud to die as
your wife. As Frau Hitler.
Frau Hitler. I rewarded your
loyalty by making you my wife.
And then only because
we are to die.
But marriage did not
give you the privilege
of calling yourself Frau Hitler.
Only one woman ever
had the right to that name.
No. No, it belongs to me.
I'm paying for it with my life.
You're permitted
to die at my side.
Should be sufficient reward.
You did not understand me.
The world did not understand me.
Nor was it prepared to
accept what I had to offer.
Those who follow me
will not find it difficult.
For I have laid the groundwork.
I have shown them the way.
Hitler died as he had lived.
A raging psychotic threatening
the world with destruction.
His epitaph, the enormity of
his crimes against humanity.
Written in the blood
stained pages of history.
It will remain an
ever-lasting indictment
of the most infamous barbarian
the world has ever known.